Tonight, at the church of Taperoà...
... "The Passion of the Christ" will be broadcasted!
- A film full of adventure
that shows a lonely man, unarmed
... facing the entire Roman empire!
- Don't miss it!
The story of a living creature
who is man and God at the same time!
A film of mystery, full of miracles and
otherworldly events !
"The Passion of Christ",
the world's boldest film!
I'll go blind if it isn't!
Hey Father João...
Why Jesus never appears in this moving facing us, like showing his front?
The living creatures who looks at
the God´s face, dies.
Holy Mary! Have you ever thought if this
man suddenly turns this way?
He won't turn! There is no worthy actor for playing such a role!
Sir, why don´t you apply for this role?
What conversation is this?
Aren´t you Sir the representative of God?
you would earn a bunch of money
as a film actor.
The true christian
satisfies himself with just a few.
So I'm a naughty Christian because...
I am not that satisfied with the payment.
Playing this movie, João Grilo, it is already a holy work.
Like the apostles, we are
spreading the life of Christ.
Do you want a better payment than that?
If Jesus only knew
worldliness, scoundrelism...
of a certain type
of priest we have nowadays...
He would possibly shake the cross out and...
go straight upward to Heaven!
Watch out your lack of respect, dude!
Jesus died for the poor, Chicó!
We can allow ourselves
certain intimacies.
"We"? we don´t. Dont get me into troble  with the people from heaven...
it's enough the ones you
engulfes me with people here on Earth.
That's what it's like to be ungrateful!
Who got this job of movie player for you?
Oh my Wholy Mother of
Jesus Christ!
It has burned, you'll have clain to another Saint , Chicó.
I'm screwed, João.
What shall we do?
"We"? Don't drag me
into your mess...
this is your business! It serves you right.   Now you need to handle your job.
- Let's give their money back!
- No way, I am not giving it back ..
otherwise,  I'll lose my percentage.
- So, Then?
Oh, dude, what's the matter?
Haven't they watched almost the entire movie?
But the end is missing, dude!
And what's the matter? Everyone knows the end of this story.
Yeah, but it seems that they
want to watch it again!!!
Calm down, people...
What ´s all the fuss about ? Nothing happened.
Chicó stopped the film just because he wanted to.
Wasn't it, Chicó?
And he stopped it because it was the Father João
himself who requires it.
Wasn't it, Father  João?
- uhmmm
So, why would
Father João like to stop the movie...
at its  most exciting moment
, which is the crucifixion?
- uhmmmm
Exactly!
Because now you will watch
the rest of the story...
right here in the church!
And it won´t be in a movie screen.
Who will show us is Father João,
isn't it, Father João?
- Yes, this is the following ...
- So...
Everyone on your knees because Father
João will pray the Mass...
that represents
Jesus' sacrifice...
who died on the cross, poor guy,
to save us.
Yes, my brothers and sisters...
this Mass was ordered
by João Grilo...
who will make a donation for this
with the payment that he received...
for tonight's work...
in benefit of the church´s restoration.
Today's episode:
The Dog's Testament
- How was it? Did you hunt something?
- Almost.
That's a nice animal: "almost"
We almost bake, we almost eat, and
almost starves to death.
I almost got more than 15 paca together.
I'm almost
catching you lying, Chicó.
Oxê, fulerage. When did you see me  lying?
- I have never seen it, I have just heard it.
- Well, you should have been there to see ...
- What, you lying
- No, dude.
The pacas.
In that corner of the Cosme Pinto stream,
where the pacas cross
there are so many pacas, but so many
pacas that cross there...
that their trail
gets stamped on water.
The stream comes straight and in the
corner it sinks like this, watch out.
Oxe...
Is Water iclay to keep the path
marked by the animals cross ?
I don't know, I just know this is how it is.
I was there hiding when
appeared more than 30 pacas.
- You said it was more than 15.
- Oxente, dude!
30 is more than 15, isn't it?
- That's right.
I will shut my mouth
not scare off your pacas.
That's better. Well, I pointed at
my yellow paca , I pulled the trigger...
and suddenly the Army Major Antônio Moraes's mare appeared in front of me.
I thought: I will kill the mare
of the Army Major and he will kill me.
I thought:  I have to sort it out.
- How come? if you had already pulled the trigger?
I thought all of this very quickly,
more than quicker...
and then  I covered the muzzle of the shotgun
with my hand so the shot would not come out...
the riffle was just like that ...uhhuhu (shaking)
When I uncapped and released the bullet
the pacas had already gone into the bushes.
Let's leave your huntings behind, Chicó.
Let´s go hunting for jobs...
I heard that the baker needs an assistant.
Ah Chico, I have just found out !
- You look like an assistant.
- Do You think so?
And you look like a good assistant .... You help the baker,
and with the money he pays you...
you go and help me.
- Do you think I look like a dum?
A dum and a baker assistant are almost
the same thing.
- Is Anybody home?
- Hey, who's there?
It's me.
that´s me , just me.
I heard you need an assistant.
Why do you ask?
Would you like to help?
- Yes.
that´s Okay. I never say "no"
to help and money.
- How much do you pay?
- I'm doing you a favor...
to let you help me,
what more do would you like
- I told you, you look like a dum!
- Are you unemployed?
- Unemployed, annoyed and starving.
- And dying to help!
- Then the job is yours.
- Fine. The job is yours.
- How much is the salary?
- Not much.
- On the other hand,
there is plenty of work .
- If it is too much work, you
need 2 assistents
- only if it is for the wage of one.
- And how much is that wage?
- How much?
- Five pennies.
- Five crowns.
- Is that good for you, Chicó?
- It is good for me.
So let's do the math.
Chicó
works for two, gets paid for one.
- I am going to do it all alone?
- Of course not Chicó, but you can handle  half of it, can't you?
- I guess so.
- It 's settled. Chicó works for 2, gets paid for 1, and
does half of the chores.
I work for 2 more, get paid for 1,
and do the other half of chores.
and I'll take care of the other half!
- I said 2 for the price of 1!
- But, This is 4 for the price of 2...
which comes out
the same, boss!
- Is that right?
- Sure it is. Can't you do math?
So, It's a deal.
Are you crazy? Now each of us
will have to work for 2.
I forgot to say that 1 of my
2 workers is a damn lazy man...
and just sleeps all the time.
- And how about the other?
- Ah, the other is very hardworking,
but he didn't come today.
Open this door, Eurico
- Is it time to arrive
in a respectful house?
Here you won´t enter even with
the mad dog disease...
go to sleep on the street,
for everyone to know...
the tyoe of a
traitor woman that you are.
- Oxê, I just went out to cool down myself.
- To cool down this fire
that you have in there!
João Grilo! Chicó!
- Sir!
- Go call Father João, I want him to witness..
this naughtyness and to condemn this
adulteress to the fifth of hell!
- I've called a priest for
everything in this world...
except for giving
a "cheated" certificate...
- Kikinho, let's solve
this matter between us.
Open up, please
- to open? Only if it's yours
head, your unfortunate!
I was very fool when I married you, okay?
Beautiful woman is only good at
cheating.
If you don't open it,
I will throw myself into the
well
And am I that lucky?
You will die of remorse
of your false accusations...
- I'm going to set of some fireworks!
- And everyone will think...
that you have killed me for jealousy!
- And are you an idiot to die
just for that?
Farwell Eurico!
My only love. Ah!!!!
Dorinha,
my love...
Don't do such a thing
because I'm crazy for you!
Open that door, Dora!
Is it time to arrive
in a respectful house?
Here you won´t enter not even with the mad dog disease...
Go to sleep is on the street,  for
everyone to  know...
the type of a
jerk you are!
But,  what is this?!
I was the one
inside, Father João,
But then she threw herself into the well, and I
ended up coming out here!
Huh, Dora?
He's drunk Father,
doesn't say a thing that makes sense!
My daughter, forgive him, he
doesn't know what he says.
I do not forgive Father...
I can't take it anymore this
cachaça breath.
- But Father...
- Eurico, give yourself respect!
You are the president of
Brotherhood of Souls!
- But Father João!
- Apologize to your wife,
my son, I'm commanding it!
- Sorry...
- "Dorinha"...
- Sorry, Dorinha.
And remember, wedding is an invention of God!
However, the devil
added cheating!
Hey, Grilo, with so much bread
like this...
do you think they will
miss only two?
As if you don't know how cunning are these people.
They count each single bread,
well counted...
and they still write everything down
on the notebook that they have.
We say it was a
mouse that ate it.
And have you ever seen a mouse eating a whole bread like that, especially two?
- We say it was 2 mice.
- Do you think they are dum?
They will say in our face
that the 2 mice are the 2 of us.
This mouse story
isn't bad idea at all.
The darn Chicó from time to time have a good idea.
-João...
-What a fright, Chicó!
My heart has come to my foot!
-Ôxe, why?
-I do not know...
I thought it was a mouse!
- Leave the delivery
for later, Chicó.
- No hurry.
- It's just that Eurico told me rush off .
- And  don't you  know that I boss him ?
- That, everybody knows.
-And if he bosses you around...
and I boss him around...
- I'm in charge of you, you know?
- You can boss me around, I'm used to it.
- Anything?
- if it is not to kill, to steal,
not to offend father and mother, nor...
swear the holy name of God in vain.
- Do you obey all 10 commandments?
- And if the lady command,
I still obey another 20
- And if I order you to disobey,
do you disobey?
- The commandment?
- Yes.
- And which one?
- Do not covet your neighbor's wife.
- Depends on how angry is the neighbor
and the beauty of his wife.
- The wife is here in front of you.
-Then I want the neighbor's to be damned.
I was soon saying "I love you"
and she melted all over.
-"I love you"?
-Yeah, it means "brunette" in French.
Dude, if the baker finds out, you are screwed.
He won't find out, dude, the cheated one is
the last to know.
- Depends on the type
of the cheated.
The one that you said is the
"distracted cheated"...
But there is also the "telegraph cheated",
the first to receive the news!
- Where are you going?
- And you?
Where does this sandal come from?
full of dirt making a mess in the house?
- I asked where you're going.
- I'll be right back.
- I asked where you are going,
and not when you are coming  back.
- I'm going to church, that's it.
- What are you going to do, huh?
And  is there more things to do
at church? Oh what a distrustful man!
Blessing, Father João.
God bless you, my daughter.
To what do I owe the visit?
- I came here... to confess.
Wow, it's been a long time!
It's because I was waiting to
accumulate a few more sins...
to throw everything at once.
- That's great!
That you came regreting for your sins, right?
Wait for me in the church, the
Sacristan has left
and I'm like, as they say, having to
ring the bell and pray the Mass at the same time.
But I won't take long.
You can confess your
sins, my daughter.
I keep cheating on my
husband, Father  João.
- Such a good man...
- He is  good to cheat.
He's worse than green firewood, I
I try to set it on fire and it just makes smoke!
But adultery is a sin,
you must regret...
I regret... but I try to
stop and then I regret it even more.
And where are you going
meet your lover?
But father, Do I  have to confess
what am i still going to do?
You have to tell me everything, my daughter.
I thought today I was just going
to set the bills backwards.
You tell me right now and I will forgive you for anticipation.
Ok. Being this way, that's alright.
Look, today I...
Are you sure
that we need to get in there?
- Why, are you afraid?
- Oxente, I have the courage of a jaguar mother!
You may come in.
It's not dangerous!
Even if it had...
Eurico already knows that I'm
meeting another man.
- God help me! Who is this dude?
- You, my dear.
Holy Mary, that's right! What
fright, I lost even the conviction!
- Come closer for you to be confident!
- I ´d prefer to be in doubt!
- Don't worry about Eurico.
- Why? Is he already conformed?
No, at this point he
might be trying to kill you!
Help me, my Father Cicero!
Hey man, stop fussing. Eurico
don't know you're my lover.
At the last minute I discovered
his trap...
and gave the wrong address of
our date!
he will spend the night
waiting for us there!
Oh Miss Dora, I am madly in love with you...
Oh Chicó! Pay attention,
that here is against the grain, dude!
And let's wake up!
The party is over!
João, that was the same as being in heaven.
The mattress felt like a cloud.
Mrs. Dora sniffles in my ear
that chills the entire middle region.
Be careful, cant't you see?
There is a saying that goes: "Where
one earns the bread, one does not eat the meat".
And you better come to work, 'cause
if Mr. Eurico catches you sleeping...
the situation gets worse!
- But today he will take a while to arrive.
Ah, disgrammed, I have already confessed you,
now all you need is my blessing.
A wise woman, João, deceived the
husband telling the truth.
- He was half-deceived, because Mr Eurico is coming there and he  looks
furious..
I want to see what lie she is going to
make up now.
You can go right away telling me where you spent the night!
I spent it in our room,
on our bed...
and if you had
slept at home, you would know that.
Oh, women! Do you think that
fools me, but I know everything.
I know you know.
Didn't I tell you myself?
No! I mean...
it was you who told!
But you don't know you told me.
- Of course I know,
and I'll tell you something else,
I knew very well that you...
were in Father João's place.
- Who told you?
I realize it quickly !
Oh what a dumb man!
So don't you see that
I made up this whole story...
of betrayal to get revenge on you?
- Of me? regarding to  what?
Your lack of confidence.
Do you think it is not enought ?
Disguise yourself as a priest
to hear my confession!
This is even sacrilege, and if I tell
to the bishop, you will be excommunicated!
For Blessed Mother,
don't do such a thing!
And you can tell me right away, where
did you spend the night?
Once someone has already read to me a pamphlet shwing  more than 60 types of cheted men.
Screw it! Have more type of people who were cheated
than bird!
There're type of people who were cheated for the whole alphabet...
Startinh from the hasty one , who were cheated
even before getting married...
the zealous one , who only likes
to see well dressed women
Go, my little girl, eat to
get stronger, go!
Sorry to ask but Do you
talk to a dog, huh?
I do, why?
Would you like to talk to me?
- And does she listen?
- Listen? She listens...
But doesn't bodered.
Since today , I say to her
to eat and she does nothing.
If she doesn't want it, I want it!
It's boredom that I only see.
The poor thing ate almost nothing today.
So it's better than us
we didn't even eat the "almost"!
Early in the morning, ate only one
couscous with milk...
- Oh, couscous with milk!...
- A little bit of manioc...
- And a little chicken stew.
- Oh, a stewed chicken...
When it was 10 am, ate
a bowl of papa.
- Papa's bowl!
- Just a few, but because I flattered her a lot.
If you flatter me a
little bit, I swear I eat!
If you don't want to flatter too, you don't have
problem, we eat the same way.
But look at that poker face!
Dont you have your food ?
We serve the good and the best, and
there are still some ungrateful ones like that!
Steak cooked in butter, Chicó!
I don't know if I eat soon or if I stare it for
a little longer.
- João!
- Sir!
Devil of a serene drop...
Look at this! I will drill until
the lump in the bastard's eye...
of the mouse that did it!
- I'm glad the damage was small.
- Small? Do you know how much 2 loaves cost?
-But you can still cut...
the ends and enjoy the rest.
You're right. And you can eat the
edges, as mouse is a clean animal.
- I have no luxury with me.
-For you not to say that I ´ve never give you anything.
I think boss, that you are a
saint to give me this piece of bread,
even more after taking
such a loss!
In addition to taking damage to the bread,
I'm still going to lose the cheese!
You Sir will put
bread and cheese for the mouse?
I'm not putting cheese!
I'm going to put a lot of
mousetrap to catch these pests.
And you need to be careful to not eat this
whole bread and get sick, huh!
João, it's giving "pilora" on the dog!
She is with the drop! It must
have been the food!
God help me!
Was our food poisoned?
Insanity! For those who only eat
fillet, our slop is poison!
You'd better hurry to tell
the mistress the news.
Mrs. Dora!
A terrible thing has happened
to one of your loved ones.
I want Eurico to go to hell!
I mean ... i am talking about your  little
dog.
Blessed Virgin!
What happened to her?
Help! My little dog is sick!
Help me, Saint... Saint...
Who's the patron
saint of  the dogs?
Saint Francis, I think.
He used to speak to animals.
Help me Saint Francis of...
Is him from Padua or Assisi?
That, I don't know.
You must ask the priest.
That's it! Go get the priest
to bless my dog!
- Bless?
- Yes!
- The dog?
- If my dog ​​dies...
I die together. But before dying
I kill you 2, which instead of going...
you are delaying.
Oh my God, come on...
this little dog is the
reason of my existence!
- Calm down my love, you still have me.
- Which is another disgrace in my life!
The Bishop is coming. I doubt
that Father joão  will bless the bitch.
Why not?
I once had a blessed horse.
Come on, Chicó!
I'm up to here with your stories.
They is always someting  strange.
And you explain by saying:
"I don't know, I just know it was like that."
But I did have the horse! what can I do?
Should I say I didn't?
Because of your stories,
people say you can't be trusted.
Can't I be trusted?
- Antonio Martinho can confirm it!
- Antonio Martinho is
dead 3 years ago !
- But he was alive when I had it.
- When do you "have" it?
- You mean you gave birth
to the horse?
- I didn't do that
but nothing
surprises me anymore.
Last month, a woman
foaled a colt in Cearà.
It's the drought,
starvation.  They can't have babies, so they have horses.
Horse's food is cheaper
and you can sell them.
- What was the blessed horse like?
- I have never seen a a good horse,
I had never seen it.
Once we chased a calf from
dawn to dusk without a rest.
without stopping for a moment. I
took down the ox at night.
- The cow? Wasn't it a calf?
- It was a calf and an ox.
- And you ran after the two
together like this at once?
- Yes, is it forbidden?
- No, but I admire them...
running for so long together, without getting
separated. How was that?
- I don't know, I just know that it was like that.
17 hours mounted and the horse there with me...
without complaining about anything.
- I would be surprised if he complained.
We started in Paraíba and before
I realized it,
we were in Sergipe.
- What about the
São Francisco River, Chicó?
You and your questions!
Of course!
How did you cross the river?
Didn't I say the horse was blessed?
That's why nothing surprises me.
Blessed horses, blessed dogs,
I've seen it all.
But your lies won't
convince Father João.
- A bitch?
- Yes.
- For me to bless?
That's crazy,
nonsense!
I told him you wouldn't.
He insisted, so here we are.
bless because bless, I came with him.
There's no way
I'll do it!
I don't see anything
wrong with blessing it.
Didn't you bless
Major Moraes's new mill?
A mill is something
everyone blesses.
But I've never heard
of blessing a bitch!
I think dogs are better than mills.
But , who is going to look funny blessing a dog, would be me !
It's fine to bless a mill,
everyone does it. But not a dog!
The priest is right, Chicó.
People will mock him.
One thing is Major
Antonio Moraes' mill.
Another is Antonio Moraes' bitch.
What?
I said the Major's mill was one
thing,
and his bitch, another.
So the dog's owner, of whom
you speak, is Antonio Moraes?
Yes. I didn't want to come,
because you'd be mad at us.
But he's rich and powerful.
I work for him...
so I had to do it, or I'd lose my job.
But I told Chicó you'd be angry.
No, João!!
A Minister of God has no right
to be angry!
So, you'll bless it, right?
- What do you think?
- I think it's no big deal.
I agree. There's nothing wrong with blessing God's creatures!
So all is well with God!
The bitch will be blessed,
and everyone will be happy!
Tell the Major to come.
I'll be waiting!
What invention was that  to say that the
dog belonged to Major Antônio Moraes?!
It was the only way the priest
promise to bless it.
Afraid of the Major's wealth,
what if by. Didn't see the difference?
Before it was "what  a crazyness,
bullshit!"
Now "I don't see any harm in
bless God's creatures".
- Now just take the little dog there.
- What if he finds out?
How? And dog is ox
to have the owner's mark?
One of these days yet
gets into a mess.
I think it's good.
I'm crazy about a mess.
It won't work, João.
You still come with your things.
And if Antônio Moraes appears
here around town?
My son, the day the Major leaves that farm, chicken grows teeth.
So I think the little ones
so gnawing bone...
because the man comes right there.
Eurico swallows snake, you sissy ,
have you been cheating the customers ?
Major Antonio Moraes! I haven´t seen you for such a long time
This city stinks like cat shit.
I´ve just came because I had it.
- And what brings you here?  Its a honou!
- Do you remember my daughter Rosinha?
Oxê, of course! Straight hair, black eyes,
width shoulders, big breasts, little waist...
- Don't go far or you will be in trouble!
- With all due respect, Major...
With all due respect, when
she left, she was a child.
Well then, Rosinha has been a little sick...
and it's coming from Recife
to rest at the farm.
But like all woman, she
loves going to church.
He asked me to get the priest to give her his blessing.
- Holy Mary, what do we do, Chicó?
- I don't know, I have nothing to do with it.
Holy Mary, let's stop him before he meets the priest.
You are the one who invented this story, who
likes messes. Now sort it out!
But you went with me! Now, help me out!
- No way!
- Come on, Chicó.
You're used to these
matters. You had a blessed horse!
Antonio Moraes can be a horse,
but for  sure he isn't blessed!
Major Moraes!
How are you?
- Just as you can see.
- Great! you look very well! Are Looking for the priest?
- You´re  asking too much.
- Do you want me to...
get him?
- If I did, I'd have told you to.
I just wanted to warn you for you not to be shocked
The priest is going mad.
- The priest? Mad?
- Yes, the priest!
He won't respect anyone...
and wants to bless everything.
I brought him a message from
my boss, but I was ill-treated...
...in spite of who my boss is.
- Who's your boss?
- The baker!
He said he was a dog,
but he'd bless him anyway.
- That's insane!
- I know , but it's his thing now.
- He blesses everything
and calls us a dog.
- That is with your boss.
With me, it'll be different.
- Forgive me, ...
but I disagree.
- You disagree?
Yes, because he said...
"That dog puts on airs because
he's the Major's friend."
What are you saying?
Are you sure?
- Positive! The poor priest
has gone loony..
I'll clear this up.
Someone will pay for this!
- Can you spare some change?
- Get yourself a job!
I can't work, sir.
I only have one eye.
Poke the other one out
and sing at a  fair!
It's a great honor to see
Major Antonio Moraes in church!
It's been a while since you
last visited the house of GOD
You mean I haven't been
to Mass in a long time.
Not at all! I'm aware of
your duties, your health.
You know I don't work
and my health is perfect!
What brings you here?
You needn't tell me the little one is sick.
- How did you know?
Word gets around
pretty quickly.
- Does it stink yet?
- Stink? What?
- Your little one.
- No! What do you mean by that?
- Nothing. Manner of speaking.
Well, you go with a very weird way of talking!
Forgive this old,
ignorant priest.
- What ails her? The mange?
- The mange?
Yes. I've seen one die
of it within a few hours.
It started on her tail and
spread to her whole body.
- On her "tail"?
- I'm sorry.
I should've said "stern".
We owe respect to those that are ill,
even if they are inferior beings.
"Inferior beings"?
Father, beware!
The church is the pillar of society,
but there's a limit to everything!
- What did I say?
- "Inferior beings"!
My full name is Antonio
Noronha de Brito Moraes!
"Noronha de Brito" comes
from the Count of Arcs!
My people came
in the caravels!
Surely! And the little one's
forebears did too, right?
Of course!
If mine did, so did hers.
What are you insinuating?
That her mother is...
- A bitch!
- What did you say?
- A bitch.
- Say it again!
I see no harm in saying it.
Isn't her mother a bitch?
i just don´t kill you beacuse you are a priest .
I'll complain
to the Bishop!
You were right. Appear on
Angicos that you will not regret.
Someone tell me for love
God, what have I done?
Nothing, nothing Father. This man  is may be crazy with an obsession for being big.
Even the dog he wants
give nobility letter...
I do everything to please him
and he will complain to the bishop.
- Will the bishop suspend me?
- No! Before that...
I go to Angicos and arrange everything.
- Are you really going, João? How?
Leave it to me. Antonio Moraes
suddenly became my friend.
Didn't see how you invited me
to go to the Angicos?
Now it's like this, João Grilo over there,
Antonio Moraes here...
He's completely upset.
Well, arrange things João,
that you don't regret.
It's called it's arranged. Now
I want a little favor from the priest.
- I was already waiting for one of these.
- What am I going to ask for...
it's much easier than
to fulfill the commandments.
Say then, what is it?
The woman's dog
from the baker is very sick.
I wanted you to bless the little dog.
Again? But is it possible?
It's more than possible. Wouldn't you bless that of Major Antônio Moraes?
- And the baker's dog is sick now?
- It is.
oh What a land to have
sick dogs, that's all.
And the craze is now blessing.
Bless all that is animal.
- How is it, would you bless or wouldn´t you?
- Thinking well...
I think it's better not to bless. Go away, go.
- And what do I say to Ms. Dora?
Tell her the bishop is there,
and I only bless if he allows me.
- An alms for the love of God.
- I will pray for your soul.
Can you join with this pray a bowl of flour?
The Church is only concerned with
spiritual food, my son.
Oh, my little dog is dying,
we have no idea who is her mother.
- Where is the priest to bless her, João Grilo?
- he Can't come.
He said that the bishop is there and that he only blesses
if it was Antônio Moraes' dog...
most important people. Otherwise, the bishop can complain.
What are you talking about?
So he can bless the Major's dog
Antônio Moraes, and not mine?!
- What is this, what is this...
- I'm asking, what is it?
After all, I'm
president of the Brotherhood of Souls.
And that's something!
The man is
president of the Brotherhood of Souls.
For me this is a case
of blessed dog.
Bless that dog soon
and we  will be in  peace.
I won't bless it,
and that's my decision!
I'm not prepared.
I have to think it over.
You mean blessing
the Major's bitch was fine...
but you have to think it over
when it's my bitch?
My husband is the president
of the Brotherhood of Souls!
- I'll make him resign!
- She'll make me resign!
You won't get one
single loaf of bread!
Not one!
- And you get your bread for free!
- You get it for free!
And he pays for
the church repairs!
- I pay for the repairs!
- What's all this about?
- What is it about?
This is the voice
of truth, Father. Now you'll see who
the baker's wife really is!
- And what are you, then?
- The cow!
- The cow?!
The cow I lent you,
so you'd have milk.
- I want it back today!
- Today!
- Even the cow?
- You're overdoing it!
And didn't I tell you
to stay with the bitch?
- Didn't she?
- She did.
- How is she?
- It's still got four paws, a nose...
- Don't tell me she's worse!
- I won't.
- But is she worst ? Tell us!
- Make up your minds!
Don't tell me you let her die!
- I didn't let her!
- Thank God!
But you know
she never listens.
Chicó! You should've
stayed with the bitch!
If I had, who'd have brought
the news of it's death?
My little bitch is dead!
The bitch met its fate.
It met the only
irreparable doom...
that marks our strange
destiny on this Earth.
The unexplainable fact...
which puts all living things in one
flock of condemned creatures...
because all that lives
shall die.
"All that lives shall die."
Beautiful!
Where did you hear that?
You sure didn't make it up.
No, I didn't.
I heard it from a priest.
- When my pirarucu died.
- Your pirarucu?
Mine, that's a way of saying...
Actually, I think I was his.
Didn't I tell you about him?
No. I've heard of men owning fish,...
but not the other way around!
It happens when I was in Amazonas.
I wrapped the harpoon rope
around my body and my arms.
So I was with the
motionless arms.
When it bit, it pulled me
into the river.
- The fish caught you.
- Exactly! It caught me.
In short, it dragged me
for 3 days and 3 nights.
3 days and 3 nights?
Weren't you hungry?
No, but I was
dying for a smoke!
When it died, I waved my hands
and some people freed me.
But weren't your hands tied?
When things get tough,
you find a solution.
- How did you do it?
- I don't know, but so it was.
My little bitchie!
We must all
resign ourselves.
If you had blessed the little one
she'd still be alive!
Waah, Waah. i Dont have this power!
Just one thing: You have
to give her a decent burial!
- A funeral for the bitch?
- Yes, and it has to be in Latin.
- Or, it wont work.
-In Latin, it won't work.
- In Latin, it will work.
- Yes, in Latin, it will work!
You're all crazy!
I'm not giving the bitch a funeral!
The Brotherhood will
lose its funding!
- I won't do it!
- The Brotherhood has lost its funding!
- My husband resigns the presidency!
- I won't do it!
- I resign the presidency!
- The little cow...
will be taken from the
church right away!
- You heartless woman!
- Heartless?
Because I don't want to see
the buzzards eat my bitch?
- Will you bury her or not?
- If it were up to God,
I'd do it. The problem is the Bishop!
All you'll ever get is stale bread,
cash up-front!
- You cruel woman!
- And for double the price!
- Can you spare some change?
- No.
- Help a poor one-eyed beggar!
- Why should I?
Did I poke your eye out?
- No, sir, you didn't.
- I can poke the other eye out,
so I'd have to give you money.
The bitch stays until
the priest agrees to bury her.
But, dear, she's
starting to smell.
Then you leave!
Maybe the stench won't be so bad!
Give me a free hand,
and I'll get the bitch buried.
- You've got it.
- Can I loose the purse strings?
- Yes!
- This is going to be easy!
- What are you up to getting?
- I'm getting the bitch a funeral.
And in Latin!
Do you want to die, dude?
I will, but I take everything with me!
- Seu Severino?
- And you know another one with my face?
Good thing the beggar was you,
lucky I didn't have to kill him.
- Finish your slack, dude
- I don't like to kill, no.
- I kill, but I don't like it.
- Where were you going without my command?
You were late,
I went to get you.
I went all over town dressed as a beggar
and I didn't find any police.
But there was no citizen to give me alms either!
That's why I steal.
I don't like to steal, but when the
person asks and is not given...
But it was pretty good
that I got more angry with these people.
Jeez, on this way won't escape
nobody in Taperoá.
It will be easier than giving
slap in a drunk.
- Father João?
- What is it?
- I'm here for the cow.
- What a heartless woman!
If I could, I'd bury the bitch,
the cat, whatever!
But the Bishop is in town!
These folks are nuts.
They think pets are people.
The bitch even had a will
naming you as a beneficiary.
Wait a minute!
A bitch with a will?
She was a smart bitch!
In recent times,
already sick to death...
she had her eyes wide,
every time the bell rang.
Until my boss understood that she
wanted to be buried as a Christian.
And the boss had to promise
that in exchange for the burial...
he would add to the will 3 coins of réis for the priest.
What an intelligent animal!
What a noble feeling!
But unfortunately it wasn't
possible to do the burial...
so it will be difficult to comply
the will in that part.
And now the puppy goes to
be eaten by vultures.
Food for vultures? that´s not going to happen!
And the will, where is it?
It was notarized,
it's a guaranteed thing.
A dog like that can't
be eaten by vultures!
- Supported!
- I'm just afraid of...
of committing a sacrilege.
What a sacrilege, I don't see
no harm in that!
You don't see, but who guarantees me
that the bishop also does not see?
- The bishop?
- Yes! Bishop, a great administrator!
- An eagle to whom nothing escapes!
- You can leave everything to me...
that I guarantee!
- Are you sure, João?
- I guarantee it.
With these great managers,
I understand that it's a beauty!
- Major Antonio Moraes.
- Bishop.
Before entering the city of Taperoá...
I made a point of coming to greet
your most eminent figure!
Eminent to the lord, because there is still
little foot João not only mistreated me...
He dishonored my family!
- Father João mistreated you?
- I just didn't kill him...
because killing a priest brings bad luck.
- But what did he do?
- Imagine your eminence...
that I went to ask quickly João to
bless my daughter who was sick.
-And he said she was a...
- One...?
- Oh, I don't even have the courage to say.
- It's an ugly thing, isn't it?
Horrible! And still said the
even my wife!
But tell me what happened, so that I can take action.
- Called it...
- What...?
Oh, it's even a sin to say
such a thing to a bishop.
You say that I give you
acquittal in advance.
- Starts with "B"...
- "B"?
- And now comes an "I"
- "B" "I"
- After comes an "T"!
- "T"?
- B, I, T...
C and R
No, but Bitch is not with R
I never thought I would hear you
saying such a slang word!
No, but I said bitch
with R, as you dictated.
And as a bitch with R doesn't exist,
then it's not a sin.
Ah, but what the priest said
it can only have been with "ch"!
But, be sure
that I will take action.
- Do you do the burial in Latin?
- In Latin!
- And the follow-up?
- Let's go, me and Chico...
With you and your wife
I think it's a good burial.
Do you think it's okay like that?
- I Think...
- So I think so too.
So, let's go to the funeral.
Absolve Domine, animas omnium fidelium
defunctorum ab omni vinculi delictorum...
- It's there, Father.
- There is no rush.
The will has been fulfilled, and now
my boss and my mistress...
are free from being persecuted
for the dog's soul.
- Soul?
- Actually, no souls ...
because I don't think
there is a dog soul.
But dog haunting
exists and is one of the most dangerous.
And then no one wants to disrespect
so the will of the dead.
Dog soul? What
is this story? I've never heard of it.
- But there is. I've met one myself.
- When? Where?
At the passage of the Cosme Pinto stream.
I was crossing
the weir bleeder
when one fell out of my pocket, a
silver of 10 pennies in the water.
I was coming with my dog ​​but I already had
given silver for lost,
when I noticed that she was like this
sort of whispering to another.
Suddenly, the dog dove,
and brought the money back,
When I went to check, I only had 2 pennies.
Hi! And those souls from there
have money exchanged?
I don't know, I only know that so it was.
Didn't expect your honor over here now,
so that...
Let's leave it, "Passons",
as the French say.
But there are things I can't
let go with that ease.
- I don't understand.
- Well, you'll understand when I tell you...
that Antônio Moraes spoke to me.
- Antônio Moraes spoke to you?
Yes. Just to complain
of your procedure towards him.
I don't understand what your honor means.
I don't see any difficulty
to understand this, Fr. João.
Antônio Moraes came to me to
complain about your brutality towards him.
- How it is?
- Let's stop kidding, Fr. João!
you know perfectly
what am I referring to!
Why did you call
his wife a bitch?
- Me?
- Yes, you Sir.
I swear I never called
his wife a bitch!
- Called, Fr. João.
- I didn't call, your Bishop.
-Called, Fr. João.
-I didn't call, your Bishop.
- Called, Fr. João.
- I did call, your Bishop.
Well, after all,
did you call or didn't you call?
I didn't.
But if your honor say I called it,
it's because you know more than I do.
So it's not true that he came to ask
may the lord bless his daughter...
And you called
his wife a dog?
- The daughter?
- Yes, the daughter.
So he meant that he would like to bless his daughter?
Of course it is, isn't it
what am I telling you?
Grilo had told me it was the dog.
- Grilo?
Fr. João, are you kidding with me?
What is this story about
Grilo with a dog?
- Your honor forgive me but
now I understand everything!
Who is starting to not
understand anything is me!
- The fault is of João Grilo!
- Who is João Grilo?
It's a rascal who lives here and works in the
bakery, but now he will pay me !
João Grilo! João Grilo, my dear
João Grilo, I'm very pleased with you.
And who am I? A poor Grilo
that is worth nothing. It's your honor's kindness.
That's right, it's my kindness, because you
It's just a really nasty rascal!
Are you listening, Chicó?
- Jeez, if I were you, I would react...
- Me?
Yes, if I were you, I would react.
I don't allow anyone to talk like that
of a friend of mine in front of me.
- But the friend is you!
- Then react Chicó, you are not a man, are you?
- I'm a man, but I'm weak.
- Very well, so I'll speak.
Why did your honor
called me nasty?
Because you're a very nasty rascal!
Because they forgot to put
this on my age certificate.
You brat! Now you will explain to
bishop what is this story of telling me that
Antonio de Moraes's dog
was sick...
making me call his wife a bitch!
Oh, and how nasty is this?
That's nothing, Fr. João!
Much worse is burying a dog in
Latin, as if it was Christian...
and not for that
I will call you a bastard.
- What's that?
- A sudeen pain in my chest !
Poor man. But you had to how my bosses were crying ...
while the dog was buried.
João Grilo, help me, dear friend, I'm dying!
Me? Who am I to help a priest?
I'm nothing but a rascal!
- I take it back!
- Take it back...
...but the bitch was buried in Latin.
- A bitch? Buried in Latin?
He means it was barking.
"Bowwow", you know?
No, I don't. I've never
seen a dead dog bark.
What's going on?
Whats the matter?
The ruckus has just begun.
Is that true?
A bitch buried in Latin?
- Why? Is it forbidden?
I don't know, but it turns out it's
too funny not to be.
Yes, it is forbidden! It's more than forbidden!
Canonical Code, art.1627,
§ single, letter K
- Father João will be suspended!
- Your honor, will you suspend the priest?
- Yes!
Why not? Do you think it wasnt a big thing what he did? A shame, a demoralization!
As for you, João Grilo you'll regret your tricks.
Pitting the church
against Antonio Moraes!
It's a shame, a disgrace!
A mongrel like that,
daring to leave a priest...
...and a bishop money in her will!
- What?
You mean you haven't
heard of the will?
- Will? What will?
- The bitch's will.
- The bitch's will?
Yes, bishop.
The bitch left a will...
a folly of her owner.
It left 3 conto to the parish...
6 to the diocese.
That's why I always say animals
are God's creatures, too!
What a bright animal!
What noble feelings!
At the owner's request,
I allowed it accompanied...
- The funeral?
- Yes, the funeral.
- In Latin?
- I uttered only a few words, really.
"Blah, blah, blah,
defunctorum, Amen!"
We must mull it over.
It's a matter worth discussing.
Let's call the congregation.
Mrs. Dora...
There was one more small arrangement and the
bishop also had to enter the will.
Are you crazy? Haven´t spent already
3 coins with the priest?
- And 6 more now for the diocese.
- Oh, what a complication...
If only I made some money
but lost was my dog.
Who does not have dog, hunts with cat.
I got a cat that
will be good for you.
- A cat?
- A cat.
Oh João, bring it to me.
Ah, it makes me sick.
Bring it, João, I'm already
liking the pet.
I will provide!
Wait!
You know what, João?
Don't go get the cat that's just
brings me annoyance and expense.
Didn't you see what happened to the dog?
I ended up having to make a will.
Ah, but that's because it was the dog.
With my cat it's different...
- Why different?
- Because, instead of giving expense...
this cat makes a profit.
Out cow, horse and livestock,
animal that makes a profit does not exist.
There is nothing but one...
I'm kind of embarrassed to say!
What is it, João, you
is at home! Say it !
is that this cat that
I'll bring to you, it...
- uneat money.
- Uneat money?
Yeah, eat in reverse.
Did you understand?
- I only believe when I see it.
- Well, you'll see!
Tomorrow I'll bring it to you!
There is no doubt.
All right, legal and allowed.
Canonical Code, art. 368, §3, letter B.
- You mean I didn´t do anything wrong?
- No, quite the opposite...
you did very well!
And here's proof that
the priest did very well...
according to the Canonical Code,
article I don't know how many, §7, letter B.
What is this, what is this...
It's the bishop's part
in the dog's will.
There is no hurry, there is no hurry.
How are you ma'am?
- Are you more consoled?
- Consoled?
How? If in addition to
lose my dog,
I still had to spend 9
contos for her to bury herself.
And it was cheap, you paid 9
contos for the priest to bless an animal.
I've seen them pay 15 for one
animal bless a person.
- What animal was this Chicó?
- It was a parrot I had.
When he was born I
worked at a seminary.
From listening to the classes so much,
he knew the Bible by heart.
Then I went to live in a place that only had
priest more than 10 leagues away.
The beast used to
dispense the sacraments.
- And what happened to this parrot?
- He converted to Protestantism.
He went to live in a Church
Baptist there in Glória de Goitá.
I found out about two years ago that he died of old age.
How he died of old age...
If you said you saw him born?
Parrot lives over 100 years!
- I don't know, I only know that so it was.
- Oh Chico...
I feel so alone afterwards
my dog ​​died.
You need to have
another pet...
- What do you suggest?
- A canary is good for cheering.
I want a bigger pet,
that my loneliness is very big.
A hare, a cavy...
Bigger.
- A dog, a goat...
- Bigger, bigger!
- I seem to understand.
- And you're going to stand there, right?
- But if Eurico arrives?
- Are you afraid?
Fe...fear? Me?
I grab him by the horn, swivel,
swivel, and shake up!
- Do you really shake?
- I shake!
Oh, I adore angry men!
Repeat!
Shake, shake, shake...
So come shake me a little bit,
come my bully!
- Like this?
- Yes.
- And now what do I do?
- Who has to ask that is me.
What do I do? You can be in charge.
- Me?
- Yes!
- Say that you're the boss here, say it.
- I'm the boss here!
- Say it again!
- I'm in charge here...
Dora?
- Oh, I forgot that
I also agreed with Vincentão!
Screw it, with the lady we
cheat and are cheated at the same time!
Open here, Dora!
Oh, now it's chipped, Vincentão
will kill people if they catch you here!
- Who is Vincentão?
- Oxê, so you don't know who Vincentão is?
Vincentão, who took that step
on Golias from the pharmacy.
- Oh, my Saint David!
- Ernesto Bigalhão had his head shook.
No more! I don't want to know anymore!
- I prefer to continue without knowing the man!
- Oh, what do I do?
And do I know? It's your house,
who is in charge here is you.
- Open that door!
- What do I do now?
Let me fix him.
Jeez, I have gout today!
Today I have the mulestia!
Why didn't you open the door
just when I told you? Huh?
Didn't I open it?
Look at it open!
And why you take it so long?
And you weren't the one who sent it.
I get all dressed up for you?
- Yes, I did.
- So, I was getting ready.
After all, who
is it in charge here?
And do I need to say?
No
but if you want to...
I'm the boss here!
Oh, I adore angry men!
- Repeat!
- I'm the boss here!
Repeat!
Who's in charge here...
Ô Dora!
- Oh, it's my husband!
- Oh, now it's chipped!
Dora!
- Oh, what do I do?
- And do I know?
It's your house,
you're in charge here.
Dora!
What do I do now, huh?
You will pretend to enter
here to get someone.
And there's someone here, eh?
Of course not man
of God, for that very reason.
How did you not find him here,
you're going to go out there after him, understand?
- Who is him, boy?
- Oh Vincentão...
it feels like god gave you this whole body
and forgot to give you the head, didn't it?
- I'm not understanding anything, can you see?
- You don't even have to understand!
Take that big knife of yours,
and go around screaming like this...
"I'll get you, bastard bitch! I'll get you"
Did you understand?
I'll get you, bastard bitch.
Hey Dora, I'm losing patience!
- I'll catch you, you bastard bitch.
- This this!
I'll get you, bastard bitch!
- I'll catch you, you bastard bitch!
- What the hell is that?
- Kikinho, you arrived just in time!
- Exact time of what?
Vincentão was going to
kill poor Chicó!
What Chicó?
You can go, Chicó,
he is gone.
- Good night, my boss.
- Poor thing, it's rascal!
And more screw he will get if don't
tell me exactly what you were doing here.
Because Vincentão...
swore Chicó to death,
and thought to kill him here.
- Right here, in our house!
- In your house!
- Vincentão swore to death, did he?
- Swore!
for his mother,
may God have her.
- If the boss hadn't arrived...
- Also, you lazy bitch, Chicó!
Why didn't you face the man?
If it was with me, I'd get rid of him!
Oh, I adore angry man!
The best woman that
have is that of others.
There are only 2 good women in the world.
1 has already died, the other is not found!
It's nothing, Mrs. Dora is alive,
and lives next door.
- Why this cat, João?
- Just for her.
Don't you know that the weakness
of the boss woman is animal and money?
- Yeah.
- Well, I'll sell it to her...
to take the dog's place,
a wonderful cat...
- that uneat money!
- Are you crazy, João?
- There is no such quality of cat.
- Much more difficult is to exist parrot...
who knows the Bible by heart,
and you already had one.
I did. I Miss him.
But , as things are so strange nowadays,
I am not surpriese about anything else.
For a person whose
weakness is an animal and money...
I don't see anything better than one
animal that uneat money!
Oh João, I'm not doubting you, but
how does this cat uneat money?
That's what needs to be agreed with you.
You shove those 10-penny silver
on the damn cat, got it?
I realy understood.
- Ô João!
- Hein?
- What if the deal goes wrong?
- There you come with your latomias.
Want it or not? If you do not want,
tell me soon, I'll find another partner.
- I want!
- So go on!
Ok...
Ô João!
- What is?
- Does it fit?
I don't know, if it doesn't fit, put 5 pennies!
Got it, dementia?!
I understood everything !
Mrs. Dora...
I came to bring the cat for you to meet.
- Oh, is that the one that shits money?
- Excuse the bad word, yes it is ma'am.
- But this one I only believe when I see it.
- Just take the money.
- Well, take it off.
- No, Mrs. Dora...
You better take it off
to learn how it is.
- Not me, take you off.
- Don't be disgusted, Mrs. Dora...
In science everything is natural.
- Well, if it's natural, take it off.
- Yeah, then I take.
It's it. 5 pennies that the
cat gives you as a gift.
Oh, thank you so much...
But if you don't get angry,
I want to see it again.
- Again?
- Yea!
I saw you pass your hand and leave with the
money, but now I want to see is childbirth.
- The birth?
- Yes, I want to see the money come out of the cat.
Well then see.
My goodness!
João, get me this cat,
for God's sake!
Arranging is easy, now for God's sake
is that it cannot be, because it is very cheap
God's love is what I have,
Mrs. Dora, give her the cat or not.
I mean there's no way
for me to get this cat?
- There's a way, and it's even easy.
- Tell me what it is, João.
- Is 1 conto good?
- No, it's expensive
but for a cat
who uneat money!
I've already done the math, I'll take it
2,000 days just to get the price.
But he uneats more than one
once a day, haven't you seen it?
But he can die. I only give 500.
And if you don't accept,
I fire you from the bakery.
Okay, I'll accept 500.
Ah, what a cute kitten. Now another thing, I have a little boy again...
And I'm going to take the damage.
- Ready Chicó, take your share...
- Let's return this money...
- and say it was a mistake!
- Nothing like that!...
- Take your half and stop being soft!
- Man, I don't have the courage
to go on forever...
It's better to return soon
while everything is at peace.
It wasn't me who did the whole thing.
- Then, we're leaving.
- And where are we going?
- I don't know, I only know that so it was. The woman already discovered it.
How many bucks did you manage to put?
- It was 3.
- So the business is booming!
Ô Dora...
If this cat uneats a coin,
is that the money is not
worth no more shit!
I was really crazy
to get revenge on those two.
Remember that time when I got sick?
3 days I spent on top of a bed to
die and not even a glass of water was sent to me!
The dog already ate steak
cooked in butter...
I can't stand who likes it more
of animals than of people!
Open it or I'll take it down!
Save me my padim Cicero!
If I get out of this story alive
I climb the Serra do Pico on my knees!
Open that door,  shameless man!
Thank God and Blessed Virgin of Lourdes!
Stop being soft man, for everything.
There's medicine, except for death!
And you think that we
won't you die after this?
- Good idea!
- I thought it was bad.
Open the door and leave it to me.
- Where's that bastard?
- Dorinha... mistress!
João had a passing today
late, you're about to die on that treadmill.
Get rid of Satan, get rid of scruff!
Making fools of us, Eurico!
Help Fr. João, the
Heaven is opening!
You will now eat everything
that the cat unate!
Don't touch him boss! This is plague
bubonic, you too disgrace yourself!
- Plague of what?
- It's bubonic plague...
Don't you know that the bakery is full
of rats, and rats transmit the plague?
- I see you...
Oh my mother, it's already noon in the middle
night, says the one-handed clock.
- Have pity on this poor fellow.
- Pity what? I want the cat's money!
Open this window to clear
the shadow of those vultures!
Before you die, João, say
at least where the money is.
- Like this you'll save your soul!
- He doesn't hear anymore, he's mute.
Oh, I'm freezing to death,
Oh, I'm on fire!
Oh, disgraced disease! Blurry vision,
the belly bulges, the gut explodes,
the ridge breaks in the middle...
and the living being dies of idiosyncrasy!
No! Leave me! Let go of me I don't
I want to go! Oh, here I am going...
I went.
Jeez died! It happens that
João Grilo stretched out his shins!
Take the opportunity to see if the money
it's not in one of his pockets, Chicó.
The money is here, oh, but
it's contaminated by the plague.
Keep with you as your
salary in advance.
And don't forget to set fire
on that mat he was lying there.
Set aside some money to pay
the burial, that we will inform Fr. João.
Lord, receive your son João Grilo...
Forgive your naughtiness,
your shamelessness,
your ready-mades, your
lies, your fibs,
per omnia saecula saeculorum, amém!
-Amen!
-Amen.
-And it's over?
-God help me, a dead man!
-What a dead man, go curse your mother!
- Oh, I had forgotten...
was already believing in the
litany of Father João.
That one spent less
Latin to order
my soul than
at the dog's funeral.
Speaking of burial, you better disappear before yours funeral.
Yeah, then they find out
everything and put it behind me.
I do not know why...
There are many dead who disappear before the
burial. I've seen a case myself...
that the devil came forward and pulled the deceased
before the body arrives at the cemetery...
- because the guy was very bad.
- Watch out at the respect, can´t you see?
Then who's bad is yours
intelligence! Where have you seen yourself?
- Devil enter church?
- I don't know. I only know that so it was.
Tomorrow at the funeral,
You do the following, Chico:
Say I asked to be
buried in the land where I was born,
that only you know where it is.
And plays walking along the road, and goes on saying
whenever it's over there, it's over there...
the way they like me, they will give up
to accompany the procession
less than half a league!
Absolve Domine, "anim
omfidelium" defunctorum
ab omni "delicti defunctorum"...
Amem!
Absolve Domine, animas omnium fidelium
defunctorum ab omni "delicti delictorum"...
- Amem!
My God, what it might be?
It's a shooting!
A time like this and I'm dead here,
without being able to give a career!
God help me, everybody is going to die now!
Holy Mary, we
are gonna die by a shoot!
Holy Mary, I think before the shooting I will die from fear... !
Everyone quiet!
Whoever runs won't run anymore!
Whoever screams won't scream anymore!
-The first one who tries to escape, dies.
-The church is a sacred place...
-If you allow me...
-Permission denied!
-I have no order to receive from anyone!
-But captain...
And stop calling me
captain, which I do not like!
-And what shall I call you, then?
-Severino, which is my given name.
Or Severino de Aracaju, who
is my war name!
The question is that we don't have the courage to call
such an important person of Severino.
This is all due to rifle that is on my hands.
If it was any of
you, I was called Biu.
Stop talking, and
let's get these pockets empty.
You take a dagger and
poke the dead man's mouth
to see if he doesn't have
no gold teeth.
-But captain...
-Stop your slack, bitch!
I don't like to disturb dead.
I disturb, but I don't like it.
Oh siblings...
-Oxê, resurrected?
-Let me kill again.
A moment Severino. I came to bring you
a message from my padinho "padim Ciço".
-Did you meet Padim Ciço?
-So?
Who else would have the power to resurrect me?
The only one that could is God! And
after him my padinho padim Ciço.
That's why he stayed a little
annoyed with you...
when you said just now
that doesn't take orders from anyone...
and sent an order from Heaven to you.
-If it's my padinho, I'll obey.
- His message is as follows:
-"Tell Captain Severino..."
-Did he call me captain?
- He called. Why don't you like it?
-I like it now.
"Tell Captain Severino, that
if he wants to prove his devotion..."
"is to suspend immediately
the attack on the city of Taperoá".
-And for what reason I should stop?
-"And without asking for an explanation..."
"that is for the order to be better obeyed".
Order who can, obeys who has sense.
Men let's make a get out
temporary, by command of Heaven...
that Severino de Aracaju
only retreat before God!
Long Live João Grilo!
There are people who become heroes because
dies, I have become a rising hero !
It looks like it's not what
Eurico and Mrs. Dora thinking so...
- Oh, who asked their opinion?
- No one, but even with no one asking...
they're coming there, crazy to give!
And I know that you too
was into this cat thing!
Didn't you like the pet?
This cat doesn't uneats money
nothing at all! This cat uneats...
What every cat uneats.
What is it, sir?
Are you ashamed to speak
these things in the middle of all the people?
Take it off, don't take it off, what a conversation
more immoral, what xamego is this?
Immoral are you, okay?
Selling that cat!
And the fault is mine that your
women just like animals?
She doesn't just like animals,
that she married me!
- Where's the cat's money?
- Wasn't that my paycheck?
But it could be the
advance of your burial!
Since you are asking
with all this education...
And if you hadn't saved
the city of cangaceiros,
I put you
out of the bakery!
You don't need to put anything out, that
I'm already out of it!
A guy like me doesn't work
for a woman who buys a cat!
Thief! Thief!
You are a thief, President of the Brotherhood!
I was in bed for 3 days,
without a single glass of water!
You ungrateful! I never let you go,
despite all your tricks!
You never fired me because
I worked cheap and good!
And please don't piss me off! Otherwise I...
I shoot Chicó in the head!
Oxe! Not mine! Give it to your mother,
that at least you were born!
In fact Major, Fr. not João do not
called your daughter a dog.
- called, your Bishop.
- He didn't, Major.
-He didn't, Major.
- Called, your Bishop!
- Called, Major...
- Did he or didn't he call, Bishop?
- He called, and he didn't.
You were coming to order
a blessing for your daughter...
and Fr. John thought
that it was a dog.
Bless the dog? And can he?
Can, can, can, can, can. Can!
Canonical Code, §936, art 3º, letra C...
This blessing business
are very demoralized!
If a priest can bless even a dog, it's me
who don't want him to bless my daughter!
Don't worry!
I will personally bless your daughter.
Tomorrow is patron saint's day,
I'm going to say Mass in Taperoá.
Are you untalking, man?
Gave him a slap that this
Severino de Aracaju pissed himself all over.
Everything went into the fishmonger with me!
I solved everything with a burp!
- Huh?
- Yes...
It was really good that you traveled
so you would not commit any rashness.
You were for more than 10
man armed up to the gogó.
And I'm a
hook man, Eurico?
It's better not to make it easy, right?
We already telegraphed to the capital, today
the police detachment will be arriving.
Employment, work, service,
assignment. Anything goes.
Your reputation isn't the best.
Ah, Major, they live wanting
that poor man has no defect!
They say you're a wrap,
abused, full of nine-hour.
My lord, there are some qualities
they require to get a job...
that I don't know a boss
able to be employed.
I'll make a bet with you.
I ask you 3 questions.
If you get it right...
- You get the job.
- Now! I have nothing to lose.
Yes, you have! If you make a mistake... I will start to take
a leather strap from your back.
- Damn it!
- what do you say?
I'm up, I just need to convince my
legs, that are shaking all over!
Okay, here goes the first one...
What is the distance from a
end of the world to the other?
A day's journey, which is the length that the sun take to cross it!
- What exists above a king?
- The crown!
- What am I thinking now?
- Winning me!
Very good, João Grilo.
I know that you are really smart.
You are more knowledgeable,
who now commands me.
Then go to Taperoá to get my
daughter who is arriving from Recife.
Left, right, left, right, left, right, left, right.
Halt!
The 20th platoon wishes to
salute the people of this town!
Itaperoà can now declare war against Brazil!
Corporal 70,
at your service.
- Oh, don't tell me that, because I will accept.
- All loose, I know this little breed...
Where have you seen man having to use
uniform to prove you're male?
Corporal, let me introduce you
to the staff here. Eurico, my husband.
Vicentão mine...
Our friend.
Much pleasure!
Rosinha, how you grew up!
Got more beautiful, got caught up and...
Your kindness, Sr Eurico!
Oxe, I have been a little sick recently...
And that's not why I came
spend some time in Taperoá?
And when are you leaving?
I mean, I say...
How long are you staying around here ? - If I could choose, I wouldn't leave here...
but my mom just wants to know about the capital!
Oxe, me too,  I could live there.
because  here it is
full of bastard.
Excuse me, before I go to
farm I'm still going to go to church,
The Bishop will give the blessing!
The Bishop, is it? Man, it's a sin to miss a Mass like this!
Excuse me, Mrs. Dora!
The military authority will
salute the religious authorities!
- Isn't today novena day?
- But you , howeverm, are dismissed.
Hi Chicó!
Eita, what a baggy man.
You are Enjoying the party and
I'm working here, right?
What?
Oxe, have you been drinking?
Never mind.
Mass is about to begin.
- Who is him?
- He is Chico!
- Chico of what?
- I do not know...
just call "Chicó" and he'll come.
I would love to eat a candy.
João, go buy me a straw!
And the Mass?
When I have this cravy, It has to be on time.
- Did you give up to go to the blessing?
- I'm going to buy a candy!
Let me buy it for you.
- Mrs. Rosinha, I am at your service!
- Go buy me a candy!
- A candy?
- Yes! Right, back!
I brought you some candy.
Thanks Chicó.
- How do you know my name?
- I guessed.
Your candy.
You took so long that
Chicó already brought me one.
- How, if was to me that you asked?
- He guessed.
- Rosinha! Your candy.
- Thanks! Thanks!
Eita, everyone here reads mind!
In nomine Patris, et
Filius, et Spiritus Sancti..
- Amen!
Gloria in excelsis "Dei" pax
hominibus bonae voluntatis...
descendat super et maneat "sem". In nomine
Patris, et Filius, et Spiritus Sancti
- Amen!
Someone is offering  this
song to Rosinha
And that someone says will not say who  who he is
because she'll have to guess
oh guys, oh no, in
moonlight like that in the sertão..
This blessing took longer
than a disease in a poor man's house.
I had never seen so much
people at the patron saint's party!
The faith of the people of Taperoá
has increased a lot.
- In Recife, the opposite has happened.
- Blame of the beach...
They say that the shame is so much, that
girl enters the water single and comes out married.
I've never seen the sea, I don't know
what is a woman with a thong.
I read that millions of years ago
ago, the sertão was also a sea.
It may be, but there was no naughtiness here.
It would be nice to see the sertão full of water.
Rosinha!
You're already a grown up , I have to take it
measures to protect your honor.
I want you to return to Recife married.
- Me, my father?
- Yes, you! Don't make a fool of yourself!
Here's your dowry.
That pig belonged
to your great-grandmother...
Rosa Benigna Vaz de Medeiros.
Every single day, sinhá Rosa
put a coin in the pig.
When she died, she left this pig
as a wedding gift for you...
who was named Rosa
in honor of her.
I pray to God that this saint
lady have had a long life!
She lived to nearly 100 years old.
This pig is full of money.
Now all you need to do is find a man
who is a doctor and brave for you to marry.
How, my father?
If I don't like anyone!
Nonsense! With time
you get used to it and end up liking your him.
Oh my Blessed Mother!
Now I'm going to be forced to get married.
Don't worry, Dona Rosa!
You will find someone to love you.
With the help of your beauty
and this pig here...
suitor will not be missed.
I'm completely down for her, João.
I even lost hunger.
Well, first you should
eat that you already stay happy again.
I shoot for myself. Hungry
a little trouble knocks me down,
With a full belly I
I can bear any misfortune.
I can't eat. So much love that it´s
enough, it gives me a gas in here.
- Why don't you tell her that?
- So Poor like I am...
- Marrying her will make you rich.
- Marry how, dude?
I'll help, but there it is.
After being rich you forget
from your friend João Grilo...
Why do I want money?
If I don't even want to eat anymore.
Marrying her,
your boredom ends.
And plenty of it, to satisfy your hunger, you
still earns a pig full of money
that Mrs. Rosinha ´s great-grandmother of left for her.
Well if you arrange this
marriage, half of it is yours.
It's called it's arranged!
I'm going to talk to Corporal 70 right now.
Corporal 70?
You was going to help me or disgrace me?
Corporal 70 is crazy about
Rosinha! If he finds out that
I'm having fun
to her side, he kills me!
And Vincentão too!
Oxe!
And you're going to die twice, eh?
Why not?
I know a guy
in Gravatá that resurrected
of fright when the
bandits appeared.
You're an idiot, dude!
Forgot that this happened to me,
right here, in Taperoá,
and I was just playing dead?
What I want to see is me pretending to be alive
when these guys kill me.
With the plan I have here at quengo you put the 2 to run...
and moreover, you will marry Rosinha!
Good morning, Corporal,
how are you?
Oxente dude what kind of
intimacy is that?
What's up, you Corporal 70?
Can't we even say good morning?
This is a rule of
civility and courtesy...
Is it or isn't it?
If there's one thing I don't like
it's people who say "is it or isn't it?"
I get clink!
- Really?
- Yeah!
Is these little sayings, these little vices
that we catch are damned, is it or isn't it?
Look, today you sleep here in jail!
- I'm crazy to put one in jail!
- And do you need all that bravery?
I wanted to see this conversation if
it was to arrest Vincentão!
Are you insinuating that the
authority present here,
Corporal 70, are afraid of a bully?
No, no, no. I just want to say that
when one doesn't want to, two don't fight.
- Is it or isn't it?
- Kid!
- Sorry Corporal!
- This time it passes...
but only passes through
because of one thing...
- I think I know what it is.
- You don´t know anything!
Yes I know! I know the corners best
intimates of his military heart.
Boy, stop being intimate
with me, you idiot.
I know that if you
wanted, you'd have arrested me,
but your goodwill towards me is
because of my intimacy in the house...
of a girl that you
Your Corporal has been wanting a lot...
- Oh, I am suffering too much, João!
- Suffering? You?
An authority?
But authority also suffers.
And she doesn't like me.
- Who said that?
- I think so.
Thoughts can be misleading.
Am I right?
In that case I wish it was so.
Well I've been talking to her about this  matters.
- You didn't!
- I swear to God.
She even told me that she has eyes
for a certain man.
- Do you swear?
-By that light that illuminates me!
João,
look, you do know that
I like you a lot, don´t you ?
Boy, look how this has changed!
Yes, I know that
you are crazy about me.
Is it or isn't it?
It is!
I am, João. You
could help me out.
Just say what you want.
I wanted you to deliver
a brooch for Rosinha...
- And tell her I gave it to her.
- Give it to me.
My God, what a beautiful brooch!
- It was almost a full month's salary.
- The gift will be given!
- See you later, Corporal 70!
- See you later, João! Thanks!
I owe you a favor!
- Good morning, Vincentão.
- I'll pretend I didn't see you.
I woke up in a bad mood today, you know?
I even swore that the first person I saw, I would stick the knife in his appendicitis.
- But today is not the day to be angry.
- Well, for me, every day is a day to be angry!
I want to be angry
and you don't mess around!
But on
Miss Rosinha birthday?
- Oh, and today is her birthday?
- I think you better tame yourself.
- For what?
- She doesn't even like me.
- What an injustice!
Just today, she told me
she was in love.
And it was, was it?
And by whom?
She says it's the
city ​​bully.
Eita!
So, that can only be me !
Its a shame that  today you
woke up so grumpy.
It has passed, João.
- Could you do me a cortesy?
- a cortesy what is it?
Can you deliver this
pair of earrings to her?
Look what a coincidence dude,
what a coincidence !
I bought it today and it is her birthday!
This is no coincidence.
It's fate!
Oh, I got goosebumps all over,
look João.
Well, tell her that.
Say it's luck itself
that wants to join us...
crossing our lives
in the web of fate!
She will like it a lot!
Eita two man old beast of the plague!
- What beautiful jewelry! Who sent those?
- Someone in town who's crazy about you Miss.
- Oxe, what a story, no one likes me.
- This one likes so very much.
- Who is him?
- I can not say, that's what he asked.
- Is he handsome?
- I can not say, I'm modest.
- It's you, Chico!
- Since you guessed it...
I won't deny that since the day that
I met you I live to die...
and I just don't die because
I live thinking about you.
I'm very grateful, but
I can't accept your gift...
- Miss Rosinha, I know I'm poor...
- Oxe, I don't care about that, Chicó.
Is that if at least
you had a degree!
I am a doctor of occult sciences,
dramatic philosophy,
quack pediatrics, dogmatic biology
and electronic astrology.
- If you were brave...
- I'm the bravest man in this town.
You're not!
The bravest guys
here are Vincentão and Corporal 70!
I'm dying to end their bravery!
- Did you have the courage to face one of the 2?
- I go with the 2 at once.
I send them to run from this city.
- That's what I wanted to see!
- Do you accept the jewelry?
Accepted.
And if you do what you said,
I can even use them!
Hey João! You've finally arrived, dude!
I was out there, hanging out,
refreshing nature.
Everything is fine, right João?
eita!
- Is she waiting for me?
- "She" who?
Oxente, Rosinha,
who else would it be?
I don't know, you should know.
Don't talk back, man!
What did Rosinha say?
Of what?
Of the present! Answer quickly
that I'm going crazy!
Oh yes!
She stayed with it.
- Just this?
- Just this? Waht else woulf you like?
- Did you really want her to faint?
- At least she could have been happy!
She was happy!
Also, who wouldn't be happy...
receiving a brooch and
two earrings on the same day?
Oxente, did have a pair of earrings?
And didn't I just send a brooch?
You just sent a brooch.
But there was an acquaintance who sent 2 earrings.
...one for each ear.
- Oxente, who was this miserable?
And which one did she like most?
And by whom was she more swayed?
- Say man of God!
- So far she hasn't swung herself yet...
But I know that Miss Rosinha like a brave man...
And said she stays with the one who
challenge the other and be the winner.
Well, tell me who is this wretch,
I'm going to eat his livers right now...
...and rip out their hearts!
- He only has one, Corporal!
Oxente, another one can be found
then I snatch both
Don't stop my rage while
I'm talking, do you understand João!
- Who is him?
- I do not know that.
All I know is that I saw Chicó earlier today
around the Major's farm.
And he sent me to tell you that he wants
meet you today, from 7 am on the way out of the Mass.
- Chicó?
- From 7 am, at the exit of the Mass.
And what does he want with me?
Says it's about a couple of
earrings you gave to Mrs. Rosinha.
Will this one
is challenging me?
All I know is that he also spat on the
floor when he pronounced your name.
The skinny one is dying to die...
And I'm dying to kill!
Will do for sure!
It must also be that
I found Mrs. Rosinha...
all happy because of a brooch
that she had just won.
And still got into giving
a brooch to Rosinha, is it?
But it's today that
I'm having a party!
I'll rip him apart!
It's all marked.
From 7 am, on the way out of the Mass...
we will put those
2 bullies to run.
Ô Grilo, did you forget
that I'm loose?
- They're looser than you!
- You want to humiliate me, don't you?
Well, know that no one else is
looser than me here in Taperoá!
But Rosinha doesn't need to know that.
After the meeting she will
think that you're the Dog of Book 2!
I won't, Grilo. I'm loose,
but I'm not stupid!
They're going to kill me!
'Cause I say it's going to be all right,
and you will finally conquer...
the heart of Mrs. Rosinha!
- How will it work, man of God?
- You will see!
- How, if a dead person can't see?
- Just do what I tell you!
Help me, Blessed Virgin!
Either I die or I'm demoralized!
and anyway
I miss Rosinha!
- Your Corporal likes a Mass, right?
- That's true!
I can't see a church
that I'll be right in.
Well I think Corporal
can't see it's a skirt!
You should have more
respect to Father João...
Since his cassock is not a skirt.
Don't be stupid, that's not
this skirt quality I'm talking about!
- What are you talking about?
- A certain skirt...
just arrived from Recife...
- Excuse me, Miss Dora...
that I'm going to check it out
fabric quality!
I'm thinking that this saint wants to pray.
What are you doing here, Vincentão?
I'm walking.
You don't see it, do you?
'Cause I think is better run,
that the Mass has already begun.
- Because I want it to finish!
- Did you bring your rosary, your missal?
I brought my fishmonger´s knife!
- To get into who?
- Whoever asks a lot of questions!
That the slaps don't hurt much,
let Vincentão's knife enter
soft in my empty stomach...
That the bullets from Corporal 70 hit me in one
time, which is for me to die very quickly.
Ite, missa est.
But if the plan of
João Grilo succeeds, and I
get out of this mess,
my goodness...
I promise never again...
Never...
Sleep with no woman in my life!
No woman...
taking off Rosinha...
- Can you accompany me, Chico?
- Holy Mary, is the Mass over?
You were praying with
so much faith that you didn't even notice!
I was doing a
promise to Blessed Virgin.
And what is the grace you want to get?
A grace so great that
it turns out to be a miracle!
- I bet it was a request for love!
- It is...
I prayed that I wouldn't die of this disease.
your heart is
hitting that hard?
It's almost jumping to
out of the chest box!
Corporal and Vincentão came
take satisfaction with you.
- Satisfaction of what, my God?
- Didn't Chicó tell you?
that he will put those
2 to run, no?
That's why Chicó, you are
exempt from commitment!
Since you insist!
No, no, no, Mrs. Rosinha!
My friend, don't be demoralized!
- But with these 2 is hard!
- You will see something!
This one is calm, thoughtful, but
when it spreads the business stinks!
- Chicó!
- Miss?
Be careful not to hurt
too many of these poor.
Don't worry, these two
run just with a shout from Chicó!
- Were you looking for me, Mr. Chicó?
- Yes, but I already found it, Mr. Vincentão.
Well, try to do
your last order...
That I'm crazy to put in
my knife in your stomach!
- Am I disturbing something?
- What's that, Corporal.
Your Corporal will excuse me, but
this is a dirty topic...
no need to spend authority.
Oxente man, forget the corporal,
Vincentão, I waive the patent...
- Today I'm here as a civilian
- Thus...
you won't be able to
arrest if I happen to decide...
end the race of a yellow
right here in front of you!
Oxente man, and that yellow one was who
tagged with me, this one already has an owner.
What's going on, João?
- Chicó challenged the two to a "thirduel".
- "thirduel"?
Yep, a duel of 3!
So Chicó, you arranged with me
Or did you with him, boy?
I arranged with both...
but it was just to deliver a message from Mrs. Rosinha.
She's there and said she loved the
jewelry that you guys sent her...
and will use the gift of that one
who emerge victorious in a duel.
Okay, so the case calls for reflection.
Are you afraid, Corporal?
Oxente man, fear what?
Have you ever seen an authority fear?
Are you ready, Vincentão?
But now? No boy...
- You'll scare Miss Rosinha.
- What's that...
she is dying to see
a man pierced by a bullet!
Putting the buff out!
Oh my Holy Mary
What it is for now?
- Chico starts counting
- And it's 1...
- And there are  men  walking...
- And it's 2...
When they hear "ready",
found themselves shooting at Chicó.
- But Chicó isn't even armed!
- For what? Revolver is a sissy man thing.
- And it's 3...
- Jesus!
And ready!
- Vixe my Father Ciço!
- My dear Mrs. of Perpetual...
Run away, you bastards!
I'm saying...
A "mequetrefe" of this pretending to be brave
by my side?
Okay, these two will go
disappear into the hollow of the world.
You can prepare to pay
the promise to Blessed Virgin...
that your love request has been granted.
The vow I made to her is easy to keep.
I swore that from now on
I'm just going to like you.
Corporal and Vincentão went out on a
career, with espadrilles hitting the ass!
This is no longer one
Chico's story, is it?
Everyone saw it! Before running,
each one still shot him 6 shots...
but they were shaking so much
that didn't catch any bullets.
Then Chicó took the gun,
opened the drum and just to face...
swallowed all the bullets that were left.
And where have you seen
revolver with more than 6 bullets?
I don't know, I only that so it was.
Now you are ready to
go ask for the hand of the bride!
- I don't have money to pay for this outfit.
- You don't have money, but you have a name!
Chicó, brave man who only charges as a guard!
Future husband of Miss. Rosinha,
I don't know how great-granddaughters of Mrs. Rosa!
- And who has a name in the square, has credit!
- And what is credit?
Credit is something that makes the fools...
believe in a person
who sell to pay later to her.
How are we going
pay all this later?
Aren't we doing
all this to get rich?
Yup.
So when we are
rich, pay that other part.
Major, excuse the impertinence but
I ´d like to introduce you to an acquaintance of mine
from Serra Talhada.
suitor to
Rosina's suitor.
It has to be at least
farmer or doctor.
But this is a farmer and a doctor!
And what are you doing
why didn't you send the boy in?
Nice to meet you...
- It's Chico.
- Chico? Chico of what?
Francisco Antônio Ronaldo
Ermenegildo de Aragão...
Correia Vaz Pereira Góes.
Chicó it's just his nickname.
Also, with a name
of these, no one decorates!
What is your farm called?
- What farm?
- It's so much farm that he even gets confused.
Doctor Chico, how
call that one by Serra Talhada?
- Farm of Serra Talhada?
- Farm of Serra Talhada!
I got a nice name,
simple and hassle free!
So, in addition of being a farmer,
are you still a doctor?
Doctor Lawyer!
He was educated in the capital.
So you know
all about laws?
All all all,
no.
- He's very modest.
- Do you intend to marry my daughter?
Hey, yeah, yeah, actually...
They are used to speak in German,
And when it's time to talk
"Brazilian" , he loses the word.
- Rosinha!
- Sir?
Come here,
Come meet one of your suitors.
- Pretender?
- He arrived as a suitor to suitor...
but has already been promoted.
- I like another one, my father.
Oxente, who ordered?
It started unintentionally...
but now not even if I didn't want to.
- Who's the man?
- He is poor, but he is brave and honest.
Mine has won!
He's a farmer, a doctor and speaks German!
- I can't rule my heart!
- Let me do it!
You have a week to forget that
one and start liking the other!
My father, I'd rather die!
But since you insist...
Ready Dr. Chico,
the girl is already tamed.
- So we're getting married next week.
- Already?
I need to
obey you, my father!
And I have more than
obey Miss Rosinha...
And the Major will be able
obey your holy grandmother...
who left this pig full of money
for Miss. Rosinha when she gets married!
- Good afternoon!
- It stank.
But look! Talking about marriage, the priest arrives!
Whose wedding?
I want you
meet my future son-in-law.
- Chicó?
- Do you already know him?
Everyone knows  Chicó!
It will be the wedding of the year.
- The church will even be renovated!
- will it?really?
- don't you think it is necessary
- A lot!
Boy, the church is
falling apart, don't you know?
Look!
Major Antônio Moraes will not want to
see the pieces of the church falling...
in the heads of the guests, right?
- No way!
Gotta fix the roof,
give it a good paint ...
Calm down Fr. john, first
congratulate to Chicó.
Congratulations.
Renovate the Altar...
varnish the banks,
buy a bell...
I think with about 12 contos
passes the reform.
You can do the renovation
that Chicó orders to pay.
- 12 contos de réis?
- If it is advanced, it is reduced to 10.
So pay soon, Mr. Chicó!
That's how it makes economics.
- 10 contos de réis?
- He's not used to having little money.
10 contos, Doctor!
It's what you
gave your employee to go to
Serra Talhada to
get the rest of the money!
Gave what you had in your pocket!
Come with me and I'll lend you the
money for you to advance to the priest
In case it is yes ore no, let's go
exchange a paper between us.
You go into town and bring me a copy
of the Serra Talhada Farm
scripture...
owned by Dr. Chico...
for him to leave as
guarantee for the loan.
You sign this contract,
passing the property to my name...
if you don't pay the debt.
Go away, boy!
What are you waiting for?
Why do you need the
scripture, Major?
Dr. Chicó will prove that the word of a
man is worth far more than his fortune.
It's not land he
will give you as a guarantee, no.
You can write there that if he doesn't
pay with a week, you can...
tear off a strip
leather from Chicó's back.
Oh man.
- Sign here.
- I won't sign!
It's just that he's got no glasses!
Just stamp it with your finger.
Sign you too, as a witness.
- Eita, I'm getting important!
- Eita, I'm getting chipped.
Signed in leather...
Oh my leather, my leather,
I like him so much.
- Stop it, man.
-That the leather is not yours, it is mine...
- and it's the only thing I have!
- That's why!
What else would you have to
offer as a guarantee?
Your tongue, to see if
shut this mouth.
You look  so handsome that...
it is giving me a thing going up here.
- Well, then send it down...
because today I'm not good.
Oxente!
And why are you so neat, if it's to run away from a woman?
- He just wants to know about Rosinha.
I don't know what these
men see in that lick.
- Do you think she is licked?
- Licked, yellow and unsoaked.
How demanding are you!
Well, I'll offer you a deal...
I'll give you 1 conto if you convince
Chicó spending a night with me.
- It's hard...
- Oh, why is difficult?
- Am I some jaburu there?
- It's nothing!
You were always 1st place...
until the arrival of Rosinha.
Well I'll increase the proposal.
3 contos.
There's no way...
Chicó dies for that woman
- Cinco!
- The man is blinded by love...
- 10 conto de réis!
- Deal!
For 10 conto de réis, D. Dora,
there are no dead that do not rise...
Nor blind who does not spy!
Oh my leather, my leather,
who grew up with me.
Man!
It's all arranged!
Arranged for you,
there will be whole!
Do you think I'd put your leather
in a business like this without giving a way?
- Yes!
- Well, I'll let you know...
Your ungrateful, I already have
who pays for the money.
- Who is that?
- Mrs. Dora.
- But yeah! She never gives anything to anyone!
- But iit is an exchange!
For my head, my stomachs,
my eggs? What does she want from me?
She just wants your love, Chicó!
And he wants it so much that she's even going to pay 10 contos
just for you to spend a night with her.
- Do you swear?
- It's there and there.
You receive 10 conto here, pay 10 conto
there to marry Miss Rosa!
- Say it's a joke, say it!
- No, it's serious Chicó!
You're a really lucky man!
I am an unlucky. I can't
spend the night with Mrs. Dora
- And why can't you?
- Because I made a promise in church...
I swore I wouldn't sleep with any woman
if I escaped the duel as the brave!
- Say it's a joke, say it!
- Seriously, João...
Oh wretched promise,
oh, hopeless promise!
Oh my leather, my leather,
that I'm so stuck with him!
Ah disgraceful promise, oh promise...
you had nothing to
put church in the story!
Wasn't it all settled, man?
Just trust me!
It is the same as
trust the rattlesnake!
I'll let Mrs. Dora know that
you're really going to that date!
I will not, that I do not want
confusion with Wholy Virgin!
I promised, it's promised!
You promised you wouldn't nevermore lie down
with a woman, was it?
- yes,  It was.
But didn't promise that
did not meet with her!
You go on a date tonight and I give
a way to interrupt the unhappened!
- What unhappened?
- What did not happen!
Nothing will happen
between you and her, Chicó!
Think of a way to postpone the unhappened...
that I think of a way to
stop what will not happen...
which is for it not to happen!
To postpone! To postpone! Looks like
doesn't know Mrs. Dora!
When I get there, she takes the plunge
on me, and the thing happens!
Make the fair, man. Some flirt,
a smell in the neck...
Or is that banned too?
Do you think I would go into these details with a Saint?
I knew you were coming!
How did you know?
There's something here
inside me telling me.
And you have one thing
inside that speaks, is it?
- Yes...
- And does it always get it right?
- Always...
It's just that I have a little something
to ask her.
Oh, now it's not possible, what she's asking,
calling, begging for is to see you, Chicó.
- Aren't you listening?
- I'm not.
No?
'Cause she's screaming
"Come Chico"!
Come on, turn me off, turn me on,
turn me inside out...
I can´t  listening anything
Oxe, of the two, one: Or you are not a man or else is crazy!
- Which is?
Vixe Maria Eurico, I got nervous
when I saw you walking down the street.
- why were you nervous?
- Don't tell me that you,
Sir, are going home!
- I'm not!
- Are you sure?
Oxe, don't you see?
Thanks God!
- Thanks God for what?
- That you are not going home.
- And why?
Because you can't go
home now, no way.
- Oxente, what if I want to go?!
- No, I can't let you go !
- Well, I wasn't going to, but now I'm going!
- No, Eurico!
For the love of God!
For God's sake, Eurico!
Now it has worked.
why?
I can´t say
they told me not to speak!
Screw it! I don´t understand a thing !
Dora has a man there!
How did you guess?
I'm not stupid, João.
I deducted!
Come boy. Can't you see
that I'm crazy for you?
I'm not seeing anything!
Could it be that I was not only deaf, but also blind?
Stop inventing, Chicó!
You are seeing me very well here!
If I can see, I'll be blind!
Well, come without seeing, walk!
I can not anymore!
But why can't you?
They stopped Mrs. Dora,
my legs can't walk anymore!
No, Eurico!
Don't go home now!
- It chipped!
How are you going to run
into the closet now?
Where's the man?
- Just arrived!
- No!...
He wants to know the man
who was here with you
That's right!
I want to know about the man
who was here with you!
What man, man?
There's no man here!
- I know it has been someone here!
- Do you know how?
I'm not silly, Dora!
I deduced it. Where is he?
Tell me that he escaped through the window and that's it!
I mean your lover
run away, you bastard!
- Ran away!
- I'm talking to her!
And you still sent that yellow
pimp to keep an eye on, isn't it?
- She was not the one who said no!
- So it was the bastard who was here with her!
No! Don't call Chicó a bastard,
Chico is my friend!
Chicó?!
I kill that bastard!
And I kill you too, you...
If I were you, I would kill only him,
that she is not to blame for anything.
- How is it not to blame?
- How?
Chicó is who was behind the poor girl.
She never wanted anything to do with him.
- Isn't it, Mrs Dora?
- It is...
- He kept hitting on me.
- Oh Dora...
why didn't you warn me before, my love?
- Why?
- Not to bother you, man.
- That's why she didn't tell you.
- Yes..
to not annoy you, Eurico .
- You don't need to explain anything, Dora.
- You need to know, because there's more.
is there ?
He came here, but it was to convince
Mrs. Dora to meet him...
soon, behind the church.
- Well, I'll get him!
- As you are so
intelligent, go.
- But you should be dressed in Mrs. Dora's clothes!
- Why?
Because you are not a fool.
If you arrive there dressed as a man,
Chicó would be scared...
he would come up with some excuse...
If you arrived there dressed as a man,
and you wouldn't even be able to prove that
he went there to meet your wife.
Chicó would be scared...
- Of course!
- But if you arrive there as a woman...
in that dark...
- He would think I'm Dora...
- will want to hold you...
And you'll get a slap in the face...
to learn never to mess with
wife of a well-known man like me!
- Friendly quality!
This time there's no time for you to keep on
saying that I got you in trouble...
Let me just tell you my plan...
otherwise Eurico gives up to
wait behind the church!
Oxi, Chicózinho...
Get a little closer...
Chicózinho what!
Unfaithful woman!
How do you have the courage to cheat in a good man like Eurico?!
- It's not Dora, Chicó, it's me!
- Liar!
I just made this appointment to see if you were going to betray my boss, you bastard!
It is me Chicó, Eurico!
Oxe,
isn't it?
Thanks God.
The boss doesn't know how lucky he was.
Lucky like, if I ended up
to take a step like that!
- But you escaped for being cheated.
- But what is this?!
What is this screaming?!
It's me, father João!
This is depravity!
I did not know that the President of the Brotherhood
of souls liked to dress up as a woman!
It was not a taste priest, it was a necessity.
And you,  why
are you hitting this girl...
...in that inverted?!
Chico was just wanting to
help me, Fr. João.
Boy! And on top of that,
likes to get beaten.
I brought your lover back,
I made her a reputation as a faithful wife...
and I still found a way
Eurico thank Chicó...
the pair of horns it took!
- The 10 conto de réis it is even cheap!
- Cheaper than you think....
because I won't pay you anything
- But Mrs. Dora, what about our deal?
The deal was a night of love.
I was alone in the heat.
Bring Chico back
that I give you the money.
Eita, I'm seeing the time to lose
that pig full of money!
Eita, I'm seeing the time to
lose my whole skin.
It's your fault for denying Miss Dora fire!
And Do you want me to go to hell for not
fulfilling my promise to the Holy Mary?
Well then, let's talk to her!
- Disgrace!
- Insanity!
7 for the parish, 3 for the diocese.
As representatives of the Lord,
we must always preach righteousness.
And that's not fair, father João!
It's not fair why, Mr. Bishop?
Because the diocese is
bigger than the parish.
But it is in the parish that
the ceremony will take place.
But who will shine
the ceremony will be me.
But I was the one who came up with the idea.
But who authorized the idea was me.
But Your Eminence, considering that the
ceremony will be held in the parish...
there is a need to reform
to the bishop's house?
Father, of such an important marriage,
even the Vatican deserves a little hand.
Let's leave the Vatican aside.
5 for the parish, 5 for the diocese.
None of that!
3 for the parish, 7 for the diocese.
As representatives of the Lord,
we always have to preach justice.
This is not fair, Mr. Bispo.
As representatives of the Lord,
we always have to preach justice...
and humility.
We have to preach justice, humility...
and detachment from material things.
- Justice, humility,...
letting go of material things...
And obedience!
Therefore, the lord obey me!
You gentlemen will
sorry us but we will have
to undo the arrangement
and return the money!
- Undo?
- Give it back?
Chicó dosen't have money for
paying the Major, being honest, will
have to fulfill the contract
ripping off a strip of his skin.
Being lazy, he decided
flee the city, and so
there will be no more weddings
nor reform in this church.
Loose how? he didn't face
2 braves at once?
So all the bravery
that he had, spent
that time. Not lefting
not a bit for now.
What nonsense Chicó!
Undo such a marriage
because of a skin strap?
Anyway, the owner of the skin is
Chicó, and
if he doesn't want to, the deal is off.
Calm down!
There must be a way to
solve this problem.
João,
you who are so known,
don't you have any ideas?
I have an idea.
It just depends on you guys.
You can say it.
Chicó made a miserable promise
of not lieing down
with no woman before
marring Mrs. Rosinha.
Watch out the lack of  respect in the church, yellow!
Proceed, my son.
But there's a woman
who wants to sleep with him.
And she wants so much that she pays up to 10 contos
for him to sleep with her.
What does the Church have to do with it?
If the Church releases Chicó
from this promise, it'll be only needed for...
him to sleep with her, she pays for it, and he
pays off the debt with the Major!
Hmm, this is too complicated.
According to art. 358
of the Canonical Code,
a promise can only be switched
if it's for a good cause.
And isn't love a good cause?
Yes, but according to the
art. 431 of the same code
one man and one woman
can sleep together if they are married.
Then it got better, because she is already
married, and Chicó will marry soon!
is she married?!
Boy! Then the sin is even more serious!
God forbid I commit
this sin! I'm going to run away!
So there's no way, Chicó goes
run away and we'll give you the money back.
No, no, wait!
To whom did Chicó make that promise?
It was for the Holy Mary.
Oh but why didn´t you tell me right away?
The patroness is from home, I have
quite intimate with her, she
won't deny me the switch
of a silly promise like that.
Even more than her altar is
needing some color, don't you know?
You can leave it to me my son, don't worry. With Whole Mary we understand each other.
But according to art.
358 of the Canon Code, a
promise can only be switched
if it's for a good cause!
And isn't love a good cause?
Yes, but according to
art. 431 of the same Code,
one man and one woman
can sleep together if married.
But as far as I know, she is already
married, and you're getting married next.
Yes but...
But, but, not half but. It's me, the
bishop, who is releasing you from the promise.
Thank you very much, your Bishop, but
my deal was direct with Blessed Virgin
and even if she came
here personally to
release from commitment,
it wouldn't do any good!
Now I only have one
woman who lights the torch.
My hummingbird only takes flight if
is for the honey of a certain Rosinha.
What did you say , Chico?
He also said that when
a person's heart is
tangled up in another like this
how is mine tangled up in yours
there's nothing in the world that
can unscrew no.
Unscrew even not, but mine
heart will be beating in half.
instead thump thump,
will hit only one,
hoping your
complete the beat.
Come along because
you still have to get that beat right.
And what are you going to do to
pay my father's money?
Don't rush.
João Grilo finds a way!
He is the most
smart man I have ever known,
and from the bottom of the quengo
a solution will come out of it.
I don't know, Chico.
I squeeze, I squeeze,
and no idea comes out!
- Don't be discouraged man, you'll see it's hunger.
- It's not.
Hunger, aperreio, formerly this
everything made me think faster!
But where is that João Grilo,
the finest quengo in the Northeast!
Able to do sleeping
what nobody does awake!
It's over.
The well ran dry, Chicó.
Not a drop of thought,
not a flash of understanding.
I'm like in a room without a door
and wherever I turn
I hit the wall.
Franzino,
poor, and now dumb!
The way I have is to kill myself!
Goodbye, Chico,
never...
- I'm going to eat flour.
- João!
What a disgrace is this! You can't
die in the middle of this story!
Get Ready!
I woke up!
Oh man to die,
oh man to resurrect, this one...
You still don't understand that it was the big idea I had?
You hadn't turn out to be dumb
and that's why you were not dead?
Chicó, if stupidity could kill, you already had hit the head a long time ago.
I stuck the knife in this bladder full of
blood I hid under my shirt.
Boy, see I'm
shaking so far, look at this.
That's how you're going to do it.
You're going to put that bladder that
I filled my shirt with blood...
will pretend to die, but let
that you will run far away.
Then Rosinha pretends she's gone crazy from
sadness, and then she will find you.
You have used this idea of ​​pretending
dead, everyone is already warned.
This time you will have a dead death...
in front of the church and all
world, which is for no one to doubt.
The priest and the bishop are aware of
everything and will witness your death.
And who would want to kill me?
The cangaceiro. You will die
made a hero, defending the city.
You're changing the subject, and you think I would want a story with these people?
The cangaceiro is me, dementia!
I will arrive in disguise.
But aren´t you too  skinny
to be a cangaceiro, no?
When people are panicing, they don´t
pay attention to details.
Save me my wow
Ma'am, if I get out of this...
Dude don't promise anything else, otherwise the one who has to pay is me.
And I'm going to get on this shit dry, eh?
Trust me.
You can start belching bravery out there,
that tomorrow you will face...
the king of cangaço!
The life here is very still!
My hand is itching to slap someone!
But it's only been 3 days since you put
to run the city brave ones!
I'm already looking forward to a scythe fight.
And who's stupid to come to see you?
Bunch of slackers, Eurico!
I even thought about enlisting in Volante
to go out there killing cangaceiro.
Man, be quiet.
- That's a war over there!
- That's exactly what I want!
The pop of shots!
Women screaming!
The bullet whizzing by the ear!
Oh! It's all over, the
cangaceiros are here in town!
- Eita, now I spread myself!
- And how about the police?
- The police ran!
- Did they run?
Then, they informed that they were coming
there by the church...
they came out the exact other way!
You know you gave me a
damn desire to pray?
Man, you chip!
That's how it is with me, if you wrote,
did not readit , a fight  will begin.
I'll even leave the weapons!
I will end this
man in the bite.
Are you sure this isn't bullet?
Don't worry Your Eminence...
They are Saint João's bombs that João
Grilo spread throughout the city.
And why is this plaster falling off?
- Blessing, Father!
- God bless you, Severino.
I came to ask you to pray
a marriage craft.
Oh, and where is the bride, my son?
It's here!
Brought the death to
marry you.
What is that lying there?
Is it a canon?
- Bishop.
- Excellent.
I had never killed a bishop,
you will be the first.
Get up and stop laying down.
This play with me won't happen!
Your honor
will excuse me,
but let me see your pockets.
I only regret my poverty, which
does not allow me to help friends.
Poorer than your lordship is Severino
from Aracaju who has no one for him.
Unless your old
and poor yellowtail.
7 Conto!
Is it possible?
I see that the business of
Praying is thriving around here!
That was some money
saved for the reform of the diocese.
Who knows, the priest isn't thinking about renovating the church either...
And there's nothing
for your friend Severino?
I have, I won't deny it.
Here you are, Severino.
1 conto de réis. It's all that
I have to give you right now.
Really?
Is it possible?
In land that the bishop has 7,
a priest must have at least 3.
Look there!
Didn't I say?
3 contos!
I'm almost thinking about
drop the cangaço...
and employ me as a sexton!
Whoever the bastard
who invaded this church...
Come out here, I will trim you bastard!
Go on the male ones!
Because with me, the return is inside...
like a candle wick
and manioc stalk!
There are two things
that I didn't know.
One, that I was a bastard.
Another is that the dead man spoke.
Oh, Mom...
Were you challenging me
dirty man?
- Me? Challenging? You?
- Reply it! Instead of asking.
- Did you talk to me or not?
- It was a mistake, my boss.
If it were me, I would
let live by courage.
But as it was a mistake,
will die with the others!
- Excuse me.
- You may come in.
It's your house...
...and the owner too!
- Show your left hand.
- With pleasure
- It's a wedding ring, isn't it?
It is, I'm married to a disgrace.
But I regreted it,
I just like brave men.
And this one is a shame.
A Shame?
A Shame is a woman
married in the church...
offering herself like this.
Do you know what I do with
the ones I find with this habit?
No.
Iron on the chin board.
And the bakery?
Does it Give a lot of money?
Nothing, very little is gained.
I don't even have it anymore
nothing in here,  can you look.
No need, I believe!
What you had,
you left it in the bakery safe.
And I took it all,
passing through there
One...
two...
three...
four...
five.
- Who's first?
- Ladies first.
Ladies first, no way!
There's only one here!
You could start
in order of age.
- Yeah, the oldest ones first.
- First the youngest.
Get ready to die!
- Severino de Aracaju has just arrived!
- Oh, and now it's two, is it?
Eita, but if he's the sir, sir who are you?
- I'm me!
But if you are the lord, then who is he?
That's what we're going to find out now.
Who is this donkey tying stump?
- Which?
You just arrived saying it's me.
- I've just arrived and I'm already turning around!
- You're not turning around...
your mimicry of people!
- How's that, huh?
- This is just a vision...
You are seeing two but
actually there's only one...
Him!
Excuse me!
- Wait a minute, little yellow!
- It's getting late...
and I have things to do. For you,
see you soon and have a great trip to all.
- Come here!
I want to talk to you!
Man, I know what conversation
that you want to have with me...
I don't have the money I was going to have...
because the baker's wife didn't pay me
the deal for me to convince Chicó...
When you meet her.
You can charge Mrs. Dora there.
So you were really decorating
my forehead without me knowing it!
If it was still with people from
respect, but even Chicó!
Chicó,
what?!
I was in danger for talking ...
walking with this
woman up and down!
Now let's go out, Chicó,
the heat here is increasing!
None of that!
Now you stay and will
die with the others.
Let's start with the most excellent
lord baker of this city.
It's now!
Who will have the honor of dying
next to your naughty woman.
Please be kind enough to step outside...
that Severino de Aracaju do not
kill anyone inside the church.
If there's one thing I don't
I like is to kill women...
but if that's the way...
- You can leave it to me!
I have more courage than
most rascal man.
Didn't I tell you?
Hold here and I'll help.
Your baker doesn't like to die, so
it matches with me that I don't like to kill...
but we count until
3 to give courage, right?
- That's how they will be two in one flesh.
- No mangrove, João!
Brave woman!
Naughty but brave!
And now it's time of...
Bishop!
- No! You can take care of him first.
- No, it's your turn!
So there is no more discussion
both are going together!
But the first shot is for him!
Lord Bishop, be a man!
Set the example here to your secretary,
It's time to end the fear.
Take both!
I don't like to kill a priest, nor a bishop.
How can I kill both at once?!
You end your laxity!
And you two support your legs!
How embarrassing! It gives me disgust to kill such men.
Very well, what are the
names of your lordships?
Mine is Chico
if it's to your liking.
My landlady doesn't have
no name, because she doesn't exist!
Poor there has landlady?
Poor only has misfortune!
Then say the name of
your disgrace.
It's João Grilo.
Well, it's very good.
It's time for your
disgrace João Grilo...
the yellow more yellow that
I've had the honor of killing!
One moment! Before I die
I would like you to do a big favor.
- Which is?
- Give him that harmonica as a gift.
A harmonica?
Why do I want a harmonica?
It's never to die with the
injuries that the police inflict on you.
What are you talking about?
I've heard of bento rattle
that cures snakebite...
but of harmonica that heals wounds of
rifle is the first time.
But it cures!
This harmonica was blessed by my
Padim Ciço just before he died!
- I just believe seeing it.
- May I help.
Please Your Excellency
hand me your dagger.
- Look there!
Don't be careful,
if I try something with you,
burn.
Point the rifle at that yellow
that's the people I'm afraid of.
And now?
Now I'm going to take a stab
in Chico's belly.
Oh, not mine!
But man, don't be lazy, Chicó!
Then I play the harmonica
and you stay alive again.
- The ballon! The ballon!
- Thank you very much...
But I don't want to, João.
I didn't say that
then I play the harmonica?
So let's do the following,
you take the stab and I play the harmonica!
Man, what else do you want to know?
Let's stop talking.
Take it soon!
The ballon!
Die wretched!
- See the blood?
- Yes.
That you take the stab,
that I never doubted
- Now I want to see you cure the man.
- Right now, sir!
My goodness!
Just having been blessed by
my godfather Father Cicero!
- Aren't you feeling anything?
- Nothin'.
- And before?
- Before when?
- Before João plays the harmonica.
- Oh, I was dead.
- Dead?
- Completely dead.
I saw Holy Mary
and Fr. Cicero in Heaven.
But in such a short time?
How was that?
I don't know, I only know that so it was.
And what was it that Fr. Cicero told you?
He Said like this...
"That little harmonica I
blessed before I died"
"deliver it to Severino, who
needs it much more than you do."
My God!
It just might have been
my godfather Fr. Cicero.
With a harmonica of deforestation, even
I will like to kill these people!
João, give me that harmonica.
So let me go and let Chicó go.
It can not be, João.
I killed the baker, the woman,
the bishop and the priest...
and they died waiting for you.
If I don't kill you,
they come at night to chase me,
because it will be an injustice to them.
I give you an opportunity to
meet my godfather Padim Ciço,
and you pay me this way?
To meet my padinho?
I was never that lucky.
But you can meet him now.
- How?
- A man shoots you with a rifle...
you will visit him. I play
on the harmonica and you come back.
- And if you don't play?
- Can't you see that I don't make such a misery?
- I guarantee I do.
- Your idea is good, but just to be safe...
give the harmonica to my man soon.
- Now I get shot and see my padinho?
- See.
- Could't you see, Chico?
- I saw a lot.
He is there, dressed in blue, with
a lot of little angels around.
He said like this: "Tell
Severino that I want to see him".
Oh, I will!
- Shoot!
- Captain...
Shoot, loose man,
Am I not ordering it?
Captain, let's go that the steering wheel
must have already been warned.
- Shoot!
Man, shoot at once,
for God's sake!
I don't like it, but if I must...
Wait!
- Don't forget the harmonica.
- Don't worry, captain!
So shoot!
The police are coming!
- Captain?
- Leave him a little longer!
Come on, captain!
Captain!
Damn you! You killed the captain,
didn't you?
Do you want some killing?
Take this, bunch of monkeys!
- Come on, João!
- I'm taking the money with me!
Run!
Bastard! For once in my life,
I'll enjoy killing someone!
João!
João! João! Are you dieing?
I think I am, Chicó.
Things are blurry.
Poor João's going to die.
Quit the whining, Chicó.
You've seen a man die before.
The only thing I regret
is not getting the money...
I'd get when
you marry Rosinha.
João...
João!
Oh, God!
Poor João Grilo is dead!
What a bastard,
to die like this!
What am I going to
do without João?
João! João!
There's no undoing this.
João Grilo is dead.
The world's smartest
Grilo is gone.
He fulfilled his fate...
met the irreparable doom...
which marks our strange
destiny on this Earth...
the unexplainable fact...
which puts all living things in one
flock of condemned creatures...
because all that lives...
shall die.
Hail, Mary
Hail, hail
Make your penitence
For all your sins
And tell Holy Mary
To came and embrace you
João! You rotten bastard!
I don't believe it!
Not even here
you get off my back?
I've looked around,
but I haven't seen Father Cicero.
- He's got many people to see!
- You're right.
- It's crowded in here!
- And there are more coming.
Look at the four you dispatched.
There must be a special
place for the clergy.
By the way,
why aren't you down there?
- I'm dead, like you.
- I'm no man to die!
- Remember the harmonica?
- I do...
What are my man doing...
Why doesn't my man play it,
so I can go back?
Old fool!
Do you think a harmonica
can make you live?
Watch your mouth or I kill you!
How?
I'm already dead!
He's not the only one!
I'll kill anyone who laughs!
- We meant no offense.
- But you didn't die alone.
- We've all died.
- As Chicó used to say...
"We fulfilled our fates and
met the irreparable doom."
- Where's Chicó?
- He escaped.
He's alive, that rascal!
Hell of a guy!
- He was the only one!
- As he used to say...
It's the first time I hear
the dead quote the living!
You'll pay me for this
harmonica trick, you bastard!
Bastard my butt!
I'm already dead!
I won't listen to this!
There's no rich or poor,
brave or coward.
We're all equals before God...
Or the devil!
Why are you all so surprised?
The door!
Am I a monster,
by any chance?
Not at all!
Your elegance impresses us!
- You look like a movie star.
- Do you think so?
- I do.
- Then I do too.
Has anyone ever told you
you're much nicer in person?
And I don't usually like
people at first.
See? The devil isn't
as ugly as they say.
Okay, but this smell of sulfur...
Is my smell bothering you?
Oh, no, no.
It's quite nice!
I'm about to faint
because of the smell!
Watch it!
Be respectful.
But what is this, creature?
- We mean no disrespect!
- I'll let it pass for this time.
You should thank God
the devil's a nice guy.
- If I were him...
- lf I were him...
I'd wash real hard
to get rid of this stench!
You're going to pay
for everything you did!
I love a tough man!
I'm going to send you all to hell!
We're screwed!
See what you've done?
I wanted him to show us
his true face!
Now, we know who
we're talking to!
We're all going
to the eternal fire...
to suffer with me!
You think we'll go,
just because you said so?
That's right,
and there's no way out!
What a hell of court is this,
with no right to an appeal?
A person has to be heard...
before he's convicted!
- Nonsense, foolishness!
It may be so...
but I appeal
to the Mighty One!
Help me, My Lord
Jesus Christ!
Who is it?
Emmanuel?
Yes, it's Emmanuel, the Lion
of Judah, the son of David.
Come all, for you shall be judged.
I mean no disrespect
to such an important person...
but that guy just
called you Emmanuel.
That's right, João.
That's one of my names.
But you can also call me
Jesus, Lord, God.
Hold on a minute!
Are you Jesus?
Yes, why?
Because... No disrespect...
but I didn't think you'd be
so brown!
- Hush!
- You hush.
You were more astounded
than him, but didn't show it...
out of worldly arrogance.
- The time of falsehood is over.
- Well said!
The color may not be the best,
but you're very good with words!
Thank you, João.
But you yourself are
prejudiced towards race.
I came like this on purpose.
I knew I'd get a reaction.
And you, quit imitating my looks!
You know you're not equal to God.
Big Deal!
- Now stop the story and turn around.
- I'm fine like this.
As you wish.
Make your report...
starting with the bishop.
Simony. Negotiated with the Corporal, approving
the burial of a dog in Latin,
because the owner gave him six contos.
- And is it forbidden?
- Man! Whether it's forbidden I don't know.
What I do know is that how thought you were,
and then suddenly
started to think it wasn't.
And more!
Rascality.
Arrogance with the little ones.
Subservience with the greats.
And whatever is said of the bishop,
can apply to the priest.
But I didn't quote the
false canonical  code like him.
On the other hand, it has just incurred
lacking in collegiality with the bishop.
Boy!
What I do here is still vogue?
No. This is the Devil's confusion.
- And the baker?
- He and his wife...
were the worst bosses
that Taperoá has ever seen.
- It's a lie!
- Not. It is true!
Three days I spent...
"On top of a bed with a fever and not a
little cup of water they sent him."
I already know, João.
Everyone knows this story
from hearing you telling so much.
But can I?
Tell me even if can I?
Steak in butter for the dog
and hunger for João Grilo?
- It's too much!
- Husband's greed.
The wife, an adulteress. If you place it on a scale,
they were both terrible.
- Accuse Severino.
- Do I have to?
He killed more than 30 people!
This devil is everything
I've always hated...
a DA, a sacristan,
a dog, and a policeman.
You're being funny, now...
but Emmanuel is fair. Things
look good for me, not for you.
That's true. Things look bad.
The charges are serious.
What amuses me the most...
is seeing this coward
shaking with fear.
I can't help it! If I could
stop shaking, I'd defend myself!
Stop!
What a relief!
I was getting tired.
- What was that?
- One of the devil's tricks.
He likes playing games.
It could only have been
that mischief-maker!
What do you say
in your defense?
I know you're clever, but
you know you've been accused.
Actually, I haven't
been accused of anything!
- No?
- No, he hasn't!
He made such a fuss that
I forgot to accuse him.
But I'll get you now,
you rascal.
He plotted the
bitch's funeral...
inciting simony.
Sold a cat to the baker's wife
saying that he put money,
embezzlement.
He encouraged Chicó
to be with a married woman...
inciting concupiscence.
He devised Severino's death...
premeditated murder!
João it seems
you overdid it.
His case is hopeless...
so I'll take him first.
I haven't given up!
I may go, but not that easily!
- I will appeal!
- To whom, João?
Even the Lord said
the charges are serious.
Wait.
- To whom will you appeal?
- To someone closer to us.
- Someone who watches us.
- A saint?
I may look stupid, but I'm not.
I have a higher card.
Who's that?
"Hail Mary, save us all
Hear us when we call
Milk from the gentle cow
From the stubborn, not now
The gentle one has calmed down
The stubborn one put her foot down
I was once a brand new boat
The finest ship afloat
I've been a boy and man
I haven't been a woman yet
Aid me Blessed Virgin
Mother of God of Nazareth!"
Here comes the Compassionate.
Women meddle in everything!
How did you look beautiful
with that color, My Son.
But a little thin.
You did call me,
didn't you, João?
- Did my verse anger you?
- No, João. Why would I be?
They were funny,
and that is good.
It's the devil
who likes gloom.
- I object!
- I know you do, but I'm sorry.
I can't go against My Mother.
Big deal her habit
of saving everyone!
It demoralizes everything.
- That's because you had no mother!
- That's right!
Such a mean fellow must've
come from an incubator!
Why did you call me?
This son of an incubator
wants to take us to hell.
I had to appeal to you.
I'll see what I can do.
I plea for these poor souls...
for they have no one.
Don't condemn them.
- I appeal to justice!
- And I, to mercy.
We must consider the poor
and sad condition of man.
It all starts with fear.
Because of it, men commit
evil deeds, almost unwittingly.
- It's fear.
- What do they fear?
They fear many things...
suffering...
loneliness...
and, above all,
they fear death.
And you tell me that?
Me, who died alone, abandoned...
even by My Father.
Don't forget the night
you spent in the garden...
the fear you underwent.
Poor man!
Made of flesh and blood,
like any other man.
Like all men, you were left
alone to die and to suffer.
Everybody fears death, but that
doesn't make them righteous.
How did this fear make the baker
and his wife...
better people?
Fear of death alone
does not redeem sins.
But it may,
at the time of death.
In the Hail Mary, I am asked to
pray for men when they die.
I do.
And I look unto them at this hour.
Often, it is when they die that they finally find what they'd
been looking for all their lives.
That's what happened
to Eurico and Dora...
when they were about to be shot.
Stand here.
I'll shoot from the church.
You'll have time
for a Hail Mary.
I'll pray too,
and she'll hear us.
We always think we can
live a little longer.
I like living...
but I've always asked myself if
I wanted to live longer than you.
Now, I know.
I couldn't stand to see you die.
- I want to die first, Eurico!
- Oh, Dora!
Why did you cheat on me
all this time?
That was the reason...
It was like killing you
in my heart little by little.
I was so afraid of losing you,
I wanted it to happen slowly!
Don't worry.
Now, we'll be together forever.
Hey, mister,
we have one last wish.
- We want to die together.
- Good, it'll save me a bullet...
it's one less for my record.
I claim, in their favor...
the husband's forgiveness
at the time of their death...
when he put his arms around her,
so they could die together.
He was the greatest
victim of her actions...
and, yet, he prayed for her.
I note your plea. What about
the Bishop and the priest?
They also had their revelation
at the time of death.
It's bad luck to kill a priest.
- Especially for the priest!
- Before I shoot...
I want your absolution.
To be forgiven,
you must repent first...
and you can't kill us.
- I'll repent later!
- Then go repent in hell!
So there's no way.
Even if I go to hell,
I have to obey the captain.
We can't deny absolution.
We can't bless a killer...
especially ours!
We're priests, Your Grace.
Our mission is to save souls,
even if we can't save our own.
Remember Jesus' plea
for His executioners!
Forgive them, Father!
They don't know
what they're doing!
My God...
why have you abandoned us?
They followed your example...
...and forgave their killers.
- It's always like that!
Everyone's good
after they're dead!
- As for Severino...
- Leave him to me.
He was redeemed
by his parents' death.
When he was 8, he faced the beast
that lives in every man.
I wasn't killed by chance...
and spent my life
challenging death.
He went crazy when the
police killed his family.
He was not responsible
for his actions.
- He's saved.
- This is an outrage, and I...
You object, I know.
But your objection is overruled.
You don't understand a thing about God's ways.
Severino is saved.
He was a mere instrument
of God's wrath.
Severino, my son,
you can go that way.
What about us?
Make up your mind!
This anxiety is worse than anything!
Don't say that. You don't know
what it's like down there.
Any anxiety is better than that.
But I can't wait here forever!
After all,
what will the sentence be?
Excuse me, Lord. May I say something?
- What do you think, mother?
- Let João speak
- Speak João
Are there four
vacancies in purgatory?
- Yes.
- So put these four in there!
It's a great solution, my Son.
They can pay as much as
did and still secures their salvation.
And it has the advantage of
displease this fellow here...
which is worse than snake meat.
See him here from the back?
- I am!
-This is bad!
- My mother, what do you think?
- Oh, I would be very pleased.
So it's granted.
You four can go.
Oh, no way!
Man, that woman rules.
And now we, João Grilo.
At least this
I insist on taking it.
You who are so known, what is that
do you have to say in your defense?
- Nothing, sir!
- Nothing?
- The moment of truth has arrived!
- That's why I'm chipped.
- With me there were many lies.
- I'm glad you recognize it!
- You lied to survive, João!
- But I liked it too.
I ended up getting a taste
to deceive those people.
But because they exploited you!
Cleverness is the
poor man's courage!
Cleverness was the only weapon which
you had against the bad bosses!
Thank you for your intervention. But I must
recognize that I didn't live like a saint.
You are being humble
for her to take your pains.
The way I'm bad,
it might even be it.
No! Don't give in!
João, this is the father of lies!
He's trying to confuse you!
The truth is I don't
I was no saint...
and I didn't even die a glorious death,
like my companions.
João was a poor man like us, my Son.
And had to endure the greatest hardships
of a dry and poor land like ours.
Fought for his life since he was a kid.
Passed without feeling his childhood.
He got used for few bread and a lot of sweat.
In the drought, he ate macambira,
drinked the juice of xiquexique.
He felt hunger.
And when he couldn't anymore, prayed.
When the pray couldn't do anything, he joined a group of migrants...
who tried to survivie at the Coast.
Humiliated,
defeated,
missing a lot.
And when he got the news of rain, he took the way back.
Cheered himself again,
like the hope was a plant that grows with the rain.
And when looked again at his city, he thanked God...
for being a poor countryside,
but brave and with a lot of faith.
I ask you a lot for just not condemn him.
This case is hard.
I comprehend the situation that João lived, but this also has a limit.
I don't think that I can save him.
Give him, my Son, another opportunity.
- How?
- Let João go back.
- Are you satisfied?
- Oh, a lot!
For me it's even better, because from here to there
I'm careful when I die...
and I don't even go through purgatory,
that not to give taste to the demon.
- So, João. Are you satisfied?
- I am...
who must be damned
is the brooder's son!
What did he have, my God?
In anger, looked at you and saw me!
- You mean I can come back?
- Yes, João. Go with God!
With God and with the Wholy Mother,
which was who helped me.
See you later,
great Lawyer,
and don't let me down, no. I am
decided to take care...
but the Lady knows that the flesh is weak!
- Goodbye, João!
Thank you sir!
- See you later.
- See you later, João.
- João!
- Sir?
Whatch out you behavior!
Yes, sir.
Mom, if you continue to intrude like this for everyone,
hell will end being a public repartition.
Exist...
but doesn't work.
Look Chicó burying a dead body.
But what am I doing up here?
Eita! But what am I doing down there?
When I think that poor João didn't even had the right...
for a burial in the cemetery like the others.
Poor man, he is more abandoned than the Baker's dog.
An Our Father and a Hail Mary
for a soul that is sorry here.
Oh my God, it's João!
João! Tell me what do you want,
If you are in heaven, in hell or in the purgatory!
Look at this bullshit, this is soon a soul speech.
“João, tell me if you are, I-don't-know-what”.
Be ashamed Chicó!
I'm alive.
It's the bad souls, that says they are alive!
Oh my Holy Mary!
Get up Chicó! Can you see that is me? I'm alive dude!
- And is it possible?
- Well if it's possible that I'm right here.
- I just believe seeing it!
- Well just look.
What is it man, didn't you say that you just believe if you see it?
Yes, but you needn't show me.
And how this is going to be now, Chicó?
It's going to be this way. Me without believing it, and you without showing me!
And our society, our old friendship?
- Are they going to end?
- The had already ended!
It's against my principles make a society with soemeone dead!
But I'm alive, dude!
Look, take my arm.
Bravery man, take it!
You're right, João!
- How is that, João?
- I don't know.
I think the bullet grazed me.
My vision started to get blurry, when I woke up, I was here. Alive!
- Eita that's good news!
- I have a horrible one to give you.
- And what is it, man?
- I lost the money that was on my pocket.
Relax, João.
I took it out of your pocket before burying you.
Damn you rascal. With pitty of me, but didn't forget the money, did you?
Do you want to know something? Yes!
The money was there, you were dead.
It wasn't going to be useful for anything, so I thought it would be safer if it was with me.
You did good, I would have done the same.
- It means that we are rich!
- You mean millionaires!
Besides the bishop's and the priest's money, we have the money that Severino took from the bakery.
What do you think if we stayed with the bakery?
Great idea!
"Miramar Bakery:
João Grilo, Chicó e Cia”!
- What do you think?
- Beautiful...
Oh my God! My Our Lady! Stupid, stupid, stupid!
What's that?  What stupid? The stupid is you!
Yes, I am, João! I am the stupidest that ever existed in history!
- Oh my God my Whole Mary!
- What happend, dude?
Poor me, poor João Grilo! Were rich ate this moment, now are poor again!
- Don't tell me you lose the money!
- I lost anything João, it's here!
My God, my Whole Mary!
- And why are you shouting, man of God?
I thought you had died, João!
And what's up with that, man?
What is up is that me, thinking you were dead,
promised to give Whole Mary  all of the money if you escaped!
Oh my God! Oh my Whole Mary
Oh my God! Oh my Blessed Virgin!
But Chicó, how did you make a promise like this?
And would I know that you'd escape, disgrace?
Oh man hard to die, my God!
Oh, wretched promise!
- Oh, hopeless promise!
- Now is too late to say that!
- Wasn't it half that you promised?
- No João, it was all!
Oh, wretched promise!
Oh, hopeless promise!
Devil of a complaint on top
of people from minute to minute!
Lets stop talking and lets pay what we owe!
We're not!
You will go!
I didn't promised anything, and half of the money is mine!
Yes, but when I promised it was mine, because I considered myself your heir!
I have nothing to do with it!
I didn't promised anything!
So stay with your part and assume your responsabilities,
that I will settle mine!
- Chicó!
- What?
- Wait that I will go with you!
- Will you?
- I will.
I was convinced that you were right, João.
Yeah, but it missed who would convinced me.
If it was for another Saint, we still could see if we could change something.
But you promised to Whole Mary ...
Who knows I didn't escaped for this?
- So will you deliver?
- I will.
Personally.
Oh my God, oh my Whole Mary!
It looks like a scratched record!
With all this mess, I forgot the money I promised to the Major!
You promise money a lot, Chicó!
Did you forgot you were the one who made me promise this money?
And even gave the garantee of the Major's right to take off...
a strip of
skin off my back!
Oh my God, oh my Blessed Virgin!
And now all the money will go to the Saint!
- Is it not possible to be half?
- No sir, you said all of it.
Oh, wretched promise!
Oh, hopeless promise!
You're stalling more than a chick standing line.
Tell me already if you have the money!
I have!
I mean, I had!
Is that I promised all of it for Blessed Virgin if João escaped.
If I knew I would give you this loss, Major, I would have really died.
If you don't have the money, it is not a problem.
Fulfill the contract with me, or I'll rip your hide!
Will you do such a disgrace like
this with your own son-in-law?
What son-in-law... To marry my daughter, you need to be rich or brave!
So it is resolved, because Chicó is the bravest man of Taperoá!
This one I will keep to laugh later...
when I get angry!
- Because of me...
He made Vincentão
and Corporal 70 ran at once!
I will give you the chance to prove that your are a real man, who likes my daughter.
You marry her and fullfil your contract with me,
or give up on her and I will forgive your debt!
Oxe, he won't give up!
Chicó adores me!
- Choose, man...
- You can arrange the wedding, my father.
- I still didn't respond...
- You don't even need to, I trust you.
- We will marry tomorow.
- Tomorrow I'll rip your skin off!
Do you know what it is, Mrs. Rosinha, I would like a lot marrying you,
but the truth is that I am more
loose than store door pants.
- Oxe, and don't I know that?
- How?
It's been a while since I found out.
But it was too late and I was already crazy about marrying you.
- Who said I have courage?
- The pig!
- The pig?
- What pig?
The pig that Mrs. Rosinha will gain as marrige present!
And does this pig has to do with my skin?
We get marry, my dad gives you the pig, you pay your debt and gets your skin free!
Chicó, you found a partner in love
and I found a partner in intelligence!
If you want to give up, I will take the lady back home.
Not even if you skinned me out
my whole body, Major.
- Even just one strip.
- So I will make a belt with it.
You may not be brave, Chicó...
but are good at pretending of being one!
That saint pig gave me a lot of courage!
- Don't forget that half is mine!
- What money is this?
This coins are from the never time!
Help me Holy Christ! That money
was collected a long time ago!
I doesn't cost a single penny today!
But how I didn't think of this before?
Your great-grandmother deposited these coins on this pig over 50 years ago!
- How am I stupid!
- Imagine me!
I'm tired of this agony of becoming rich, becoming poor, becoming rich, becoming poor!
And I'm tired of this agony...
to be whole, to be without a strip,
to be whole, to be without a strip!
The party is really good, but it's time to fullfil the contract!
- It's soon...
- Don't worry...
That knife is sharp!
Wouldn't you have an anesthesia?
Wait, my father.
- What was on the contract?
- 10 contos de réis or a leather strap!
- 10 contos de réis...
... or a leather strap of him?
- Yes!
- Leather, leather?
- Leather, leather!
- Just leather?
- Do you think is little?
It's not little, but it isn't too much!
It's just a strap!
One strap, without a blood drop because blood wasn't on the contract!
What history is this?
The only word you'd pronounced on this contract was leather!
No one had talked about blood, hadn't it?
That's right, I didn't noticed this before.
Or you sir take a leather strap without taking the blood...
or you sir doesn't take anything off!
I should have bled you
by the neck, you bastard bitch!
I just don't do it, because the worst punishment
that I can give to my daughter...
is to let her marry
a disgrace like you!
Loose, poor...
- Clumsy!
- Kindness of yours!
Get out of here for the sixth generation!
I am able to
set fire to this house...
but I don't leave a penny for
lady, Mrs. Rosinha!
Everyone poor again!
Not again, my son.
This is my first time.
That's right my flower, you gave the
chest strike in reverse.
I was thinking if it wasn't better that way.
Who knows if I get rich I wouldn't end up like the baker?
And then with the misfortune, we get used to it!
Talking about it, I am getting hungry of the mullet.
Luckily,  I carried one
piece of the marrige cake.
Oh no, Miss Rosinha, you are already learning to be poor!
An alms for God's sake?
It's for me to take the belly out of misery.
Sir apologize us, but
belly in misery here there are already three.
Take it, sir!
- And go with God.
- And you with Him.
Oh no Miss Rosinha, it's gone
almost all the food!
Let it go, he is also a son of God.
Jesus sometimes disguises himself as a beggar...
to test the man's goodness.
It might even happen
but that one was not, no!
- Oxe, how do you know?
- Jesus? Black like that?
Why not?
I met someone in Cabaceiras that had met Jesus Christ.
- Where, Chicó?
- In Heaven...
Says that there the pilgrimage is a thousand times
greater than that of Juazeiro.
This dude told me he saw Jesus Christ.
sitting on the throne with a
bunch of little angels around,
just like in a painting.
He told me that
paradise is on the side
of Bahia, that's why Christ is black.
And how did he told you dude, if he was already dead?
I don't know...
I only know that so it was!